Wow, it was barely an
inch when we went in.
It's so beautiful.
It's good, it's good, it's good.
I can't feel my fingers.
Thank you.
...do anything for love
You do not like this song.
I would do anything for love
You have to turn it off.
But I won't do that
Oh, no, I won't...
I'm married to a cheeser! Please, stop!
- You love it. Say you love it.
- Stop!
Stop it!
- You love that song.
- Oh, Leo.
Hey, I have this theory.
That a girl's guaranteed to get
preggers if she does it in a car.
What?
I have a theory, too.
My theory is about moments.
Moments of impact.
My theory is that these
moments of impact,
these flashes of high intensity that
completely turn our lives upside down,
actually end up defining who we are.
Thanks.
Next in line.
One of my absolute favorite moments.
You forgot your permit.
Yeah. Well, I just sort of come
here to enjoy the two-hour line.
The permit's sort of a bonus.
The Art Institute.
- You work there?
- No, I'm a student.
I'm Paige.
I'm sorry. I'm Leo.
Well, thank you for this, Leo.
You know what, I noticed,
in a totally non-threatening way,
we have the same RPP zone.
Is that right?
Yup.
- You have impressive powers of observation.
- Yes.
What's an RPP zone?
Residential permit parking zone.
That sounds intimate.
Yeah.
Okay.
What I was thinking is that...
I think we owe it to ourselves,
eally, to maybe get a drink,
out of respect for our
zone compatibility and all.
- Okay_
- Okay?
All right, okay.
After you.
Pick a hand. Pick a hand. Pick a hand.
- That one.
- Here we go.
This is good.
Let me know if you need anything else.
- Did you just fart?
- No.
Maybe a little.
That is so twisted.
But totally romantic.
God, I'm so in love with you, it's insane.
As you know, your wife's CT scan
showed intracranial hemorrhaging.
We purposely keep patients
with traumatic brain injuries
in a comatose state in
order to calm their systems
and allow the brain time to heal itself
while the swelling subsides.
And then we slowly
wean them off it. Now...
The thing is,
each one of us is the sum total of
every moment that
we've ever experienced,
with all the people we've ever known.
And it's these moments
that become our history.
Like our own personal greatest hits
of memories that we play
and replay in our minds
over and over again.
Aren't you hungry?
- Hey.
- Hi.
- What you doing?
- Nothing.
- Really?
- No.
- What's that?
- Nothing.
Nothing? Food's ready.
Look, if you keep feeding that fleabag,
it's gonna keep coming back and I'm allergic.
Like you claim to be allergic to cilantro?
- I can't stand cilantro.
- Exactly. But you're not allergic.
Does anybody want strawberries
I bought at the farmers' market?
- Buying groceries, bad sign.
- What?
- And we all know what that means.
- I like her.
She's like our mascot.
Thanks, I think.
I would rather have her than that
ferret you tried to make us adopt.
- And she makes great coffee. Let's keep her.
- Thank you.
- Have some.
"Movie"? I think you spelled "movie" wrong.
No.
Told you.
Yes.
I vow to help you love life,
to always hold you with tenderness,
and to have the patience that love demands.
To speak when words are needed
and to share the silence when they're not.
To agree to disagree on red velvet cake.
And to live within the warmth of
your heart and always call it home.
Wow, you set the bar kind of high.
Did you write your vows on a menu?
Yeah. Why?
I vow to fiercely love you
in all your forms, now and forever.
I promise to never forget that
this is a once-in-a-lifetime love.
And to always know in the
deepest part of my soul
that no matter what challenges
might carry us apart,
that we'll always find the
way back to each other.
Do you take each other
as spouses forever?
I do.
Then by the power vested in
me by the State of Illinois, I...
Security.
I now pronounce you man and
wife and best friends for life.
Kiss! Run!
I have one piece. One piece.
It's... It's not happening.
I don't...
Oh, my God.
- You're gonna be fine.
- Oh, my God. I'm gonna have to call them.
I'm gonna have to call them
and tell them that I can't do it.
Come to bed with me.
Come on. I know you
wanna come to bed with me.
Don't!
Oh, no, please, no.
Stop it!
I think this one's coming along fine.
I mean, I know it's not finished,
but I'm already starting to see a mood.
It's got like a darkening
curtain thing happening there,
and then a competing light element, there.
It's abstract, but, I mean, I don't know,
I kind of think it's already powerful.
What?
You totally love me.
- Yeah, I do.
- Yeah.
I know because this is my piece,
and that's the scrap pile,
which I'm now saving.
A moment of total physical, mental,
and every other kind of love.
Don't crowd her.
She's gonna be a little groggy,
so let's just give her some space.
Hey.
It's so good to see you.
Paige?
It's okay. You're in the hospital.
You were in a car accident.
You hit your head, but you're okay.
We just kept you asleep for a little while.
How do you feel?
My head hurts.
Yeah, well, that's perfectly normal.
I'll get you something for that.
Was anyone else hurt, Doctor?
Paige, you know who I am, right?
Yeah. You're my doctor.
I'm your husband.
Paige?
- Mr. Collins?
- You said things were very good.
A brain injury isn't like
a broken bone or a laceration.
Brains are much less predictable.
Sometimes, due to the way the
swelling tissue presses against the skull,
-it can cause some impairment.
- Some impairment?
She doesn't remember me.
Even though she's awake, the swelling
can cause confusion or memory loss,
erratic mood swings.
- What?
- But that's normal.
So, that's my theory.
That these moments of
impact define who we are.
But what I never considered
was what if, one day, you could
no longer remember any of them?
Hi.
- What are you up to?
- Sleeping.
Right.
I brought you some clothes.
Thank you.
I'm kind of hungry.
Okay.
Come on.
So, I just wanted to verify
a few things with you about me,
about us.
- Great.
- So, we're married?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
And I have weird hair.
I think that's taking a narrow view.
You said it takes too long to straighten
and you'd rather use that time
to work in your studio.
My studio? Why do I have a studio?
You're an artist.
Sculptor. A really good one.
Right now, you're working on four
pieces for the Tribune Tower lobby,
which is huge.
Everyone in town
wanted that commission.
But your show at the MCA's 12 x 12
was amazing, so you won it.
What about my law degree?
I don't have a law degree?
I think you were a few credits shy.
Last time I wanted to be an artist,
I was in high school.
I think you need to look at it like a win.
- Traumatic brain injury is a win?
- You're an idiot.
If she doesn't remember who you are,
then she doesn't remember
all the stupid shit you ever did.
You can start over, wipe the slate clean.
I'm just worried if she
doesn't remember you,
how's she going to remember
she's in love with you? What?
I was frankly a little stunned
she went for you the first time.
If anything, you've
become less attractive.
You guys are a great support system.
Seriously, though.
What if she doesn't remember me?
Then what?
She's gonna remember you.
She's gonna remember all of us.
We're her family.
Yeah, you're right.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for my wife, Paige Collins.
She was right over here yesterday.
Well, it looks like they moved
her up to the VIP floor.
- That sounds expensive.
- It's a donor's wing.
Just go down here and take the elevator
to the second floor and make a right.
Okay. Thanks.
Paige, your long-term
memory recall is intact
and I'm very optimistic the rest of your
memory is going to improve with time.
Mr. Collins, I'm so glad you're here.
This is bizarre. I'm Leo, Paige's husband.
Do you know how disconcerting
it was to hear second-hand
that my daughter had
been in the ICU for weeks
and we hadn't been told?
- You should have called us.
- I'm sorry.
You've never met my parents?
I don't understand.
Why haven't you met him?
So, Doctor, now what is the next step?
The sooner she settles back into her life,
her normal routine, the better.
Starting in a week or so,
I'm gonna recommend
that Paige see a neural psychologist.
- Okay.
- Whatever she needs.
Therapy, specialists,
I'll make sure she gets the best.
You'll come home where
I can take care of you.
Mom can make up your old room,
and I can take some time off work.
I don't mean to be disrespectful,
'cause we really appreciate that,
but you just heard Paige's doctor say
that she needs to go back
to her normal routine.
Her life with me is her normal routine.
Yes, but that's a life
she doesn't remember.
She will. That's what her doctor
just got through saying.
No. What she said was that
maybe Paige will remember.
Now, why not let her come home
and recover with people that she knows?
- And loves?
- We're only trying to do the best for Paige.
That's interesting, 'cause you
haven't even asked her once.
- Well, no, but...
- What I really need is for everyone
to just stop bickering!
Listen, none of this needs
to be decided right now.
No. Sorry.
I think you should all head
home, get some rest.
I'm sure everyone could use it.
How is it that you're my husband
and you've never met my family?
You haven't spoken to them in years.
Why would I ever stop
speaking to my family?
It all went down before we met.
- And we never talked about it?
- No, we did.
So?
For starters, you wanted to move
into the city and go to the Art Institute.
And your father insisted
that you stay in law school.
He had some pretty strict views
on what you ought to be doing.
Things just spiraled from there.
Okay. Look, what I remember
is being in law school
and being engaged to Jeremy.
I... I don't know.
Paige.
Okay, babe, babe, just, just...
The best thing to do at this point
is to go back to your life with me.
You heard what the doctor said.
It's the best thing for your recovery.
Okay, but I don't know you.
And I'm just supposed to get in your
car and go and live at your place?
- It's our place.
- Without any proof of us even being in love?
Other than our marriage?
People get married for all
kinds of different reasons.
- Okay. Like?
- Like for a green card.
I'm from Cincinnati.
Did I keep a journal?
No, not that I know of.
I guess this is all he could find.
Oh, well. It looks fine, honey.
I mean, we're just going home, so...
- It's horrible...
- Paige?
I understand you're finally leaving us.
Yes, that's what they tell me.
So, no driving until I give you the say-so.
But other than that, I'm gonna
see you in four to six weeks.
- All right?
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you, Doctor, for everything.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Okay.
- You ready? Let's go.
Wait, hold on. I got a voice-mail.
It's from before the accident.
- You said you wanted evidence.
- Okay, yeah. Well, let's have a listen.
Hey, baby.
I'm sorry, I'm still at my studio.
I miss you so bad my sculptures
are starting to look like you.
So, what are you doing later?
I kind of need some Leo time,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah. Anyway, call me back.
Love you.
I don't know, I guess in listening back
to it, it doesn't exactly prove anything.
No, no, it's...
It's cute. I mean, I sound happy.
Okay, look. Think about it.
You quit law school,
you broke off your engagement
and you moved into the city.
Those were all choices that you made,
way before you even met me.
I think that you owe it to yourself
to honor those decisions,
at least for right now.
This is a mistake, Paige.
I promise that I will take care of her.
Please, come home with me.
Come home with me.
We'll figure this out together.
I guess I could just try it out
to see if it would help my memory and...
I could always come home
if I change my mind.
I married him.
It must have been for some reason.
- A guarded endorsement.
- But I will take it.
I look like a freak.
I think you look great.
- Where do we live?
- On the north side.
Who's the president?
- Of the country?
- Yeah.
Obama.
The senator?
Yeah. You voted for him.
I did?
Welcome home.
After you.
Surprise!
It's good to see you.
We were there every day at the hospital,
but Leo didn't want us to overwhelm you.
- Yeah. They were. Every day.
- We really missed you.
I gather we're close?
I'm Sonia. And this is my boyfriend Kyle.
- Hey, Paige.
- And this is Jim.
- You look great, Paige.
- And Lily.
Hey. What, were you, like,
working out at the hospital?
- Hey, Paige.
- And Josh.
I... Sorry, I... Excuse me.
Thank you all for coming.
I'm sorry it ended early.
It's all right. Take care, Leo.
Are you okay?
What do you think?
I know. It's a lot to take in.
No.
A lot to take in would've
been coming home,
to a strange apartment,
with a man I don't know.
That would be a lot to take in.
But coming home to all of that,
plus a house full of people
pulling on me, and hugging me,
and crying in my face,
and talking about more shit
that I don't remember,
that's not a lot to take in,
that's total bullshit.
You're right.
It was only supposed to be a few people.
Will you please just get out?
Paige, I'm sorry.
Are you honestly not
gonna leave me alone?
- I'm sorry.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God. Oh, my mother's gonna kill me.
- Good morning.
- What?
- You didn't knock!
It's habit. I'm sorry.
It's not like you haven't seen it before.
Come on.
This is not funny. You should knock.
I'm sorry.
- You look nice.
- Really?
This is about the only piece of
my clothing I feel comfortable in.
That's mine, actually.
No, it's fine.
What?
You're looking at me like
I'm some kind of zoo animal.
Sorry, I don't know. I'm just trying
to figure this out, too, I guess.
You normally do all this?
This is my apology for last night.
That was such a bonehead move.
I just wasn't thinking.
No, please. I'm sorry. I...
I don't want you to
worry about me, okay?
Just go about your normal routine and...
Do you work? Do you have a job?
Yeah. Well, that's if I'm still in business.
I own a recording studio.
Cool.
So, what is my routine?
What do I do all day?
Well...
You usually get up and make coffee.
- All right.
- No, no, no. I got it, I got it, I got it.
I did it this morning, I think.
And then you... No, don't.
That one's for me.
You don't eat meat.
Then you check e-mails and pay bills.
Okay.
Which I'm betting that you don't
remember any of the passwords
or account numbers, huh?
- So, I guess I'll do that.
- Okay.
And then you go down to your studio.
I could take you down there,
show you what you're working on.
You know what? We don't have
to rehash everything right now.
I mean, just...
You go to work, and we can make
flashcards later, or something.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
Okay. Well, your, look...
You got keys, phone here.
If you need me, all my
numbers are on there.
- Okay-
- All right.
- Yup.
Have a good day.
- What's up, Lil?
- Hey.
Fill me in.
That guy, Pointy Shoes?
He's a really bad kisser.
I don't think I'm gonna
keep him in rotation.
Okay.
Honestly, though, it's actually been hell.
Yesterday, we were
somehow double-booked.
Too many clients,
that's a high-class problem.
Yeah, but with only one studio,
it's pretty impossible to take on both gigs.
Right? So, Dune Advertising weren't flexible
and they rebooked over at Soundspace.
Wait? What? Come on. That's a big account.
They should always be prioritized.
- You know that.
- Yeah. Look...
I can't run the sessions and
handle account services, right?
This isn't a one-woman operation.
- It's not like I flaked or something.
- I know, I get it. I'm not mad.
I'm just... I'm just saying shit's slipping.
Well, I'm here now.
- How's she doing?
- She's getting there.
She's...
Look, thanks.
It'll be fine.
Okay. Good.
So, you'll be at the 3:30 pitch?
Of course.
I'm going to head home,
then change, and check on Paige,
- but I'll be there.
- Okay.
I vow to help you love life,
to always hold you with tenderness,
and to have the patience
that love demands.
To speak when words are needed
and to share the silence when they're not.
To agree to disagree on red velvet cake.
And to live within the warmth of
your heart and always call it home.
Did you write your vows on a menu?
Weird.
I vow to fiercely love you
in all your forms, now and forever.
I promise to never forget
that this is a once-in-a-lifetime love.
And to always know in the
deepest part of my soul,
no matter what challenges
might carry us apart,
that we'll always find the
way back to each other.
- Hi.
Could I have a...
One of these?
You don't want the usual?
I have a usual?
That would be perfect.
I'll have the usual.
- All right.
- Here you go.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Paige?
Can I help you?
Could I borrow your phone?
Hello?
Hey, Lil. No, I know it's 3:30.
Look, I can't. I can't. I gotta find Paige.
No, no. I don't know. Make it up.
I'm sorry. I didn't know who else to call.
Get in, sweetheart. Get in.
Oh, sweetie.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
Where you been?
I was starting to get a little worried.
Thought something
might've happened to you.
Sorry. I was lost, physically.
Mentally, I guess, as well.
Well, you should've called me.
Yeah, I forgot the phone and I
don't know your number by heart,
so I called my mom and we made
a day of it, which was great.
She invited us for dinner tonight.
Dinner? Okay.
You don't have to go.
Well, you're not allowed to drive,
so I do have to go.
But that's not the point.
You know, maybe I'm gonna wake up
tomorrow and remember everything,
but right now they're the
only thing I'm sure about.
Okay.
We'll go.
- Okay.
- Are you gonna change?
Changing-
It's just a left up here at the Caldwells',
and then a right at the cul-de-sac,
and we're six houses in on the right.
The Prestleys got a new mailbox. So cute.
You know, this arrangement
doesn't exactly say,
"I'm sorry that we haven't spoken,
"but now that I have a brain injury,
maybe you can overlook it."
You're right.
We should've got them forget-me-nots.
That's funny.
Actually, that is funny.
So, well, you've already met my parents,
but my dad will say to call him Bill,
but he prefers Mr. Thornton.
- And my sister's name is...
- Gwen.
I know a lot about your family, Paige.
- Right. Yeah.
- We're married. You know?
- Oh, my God, you're engaged!
- I know.
- You guys make a really cute couple.
- Thanks, Paige.
It has been forever.
- Has it?
- Yeah.
The weird thing is that everyone
looks a little bit older.
- Really?
- Yeah. You, especially.
I'm... I'm so happy to have you back.
In honor of Paige being home,
I made your favorite dinner.
Filet mignon.
Please. Please. Sit down.
Before we start, I think this
evening deserves a toast.
Darling?
Well, I... I would like to drink to my family.
I am so fortunate to have these
three beautiful women in my life
and, when we're all together,
that fortune just multiplies.
Paige, honey, welcome home.
To family.
So, Leo, what about your family?
Do you see them often?
- No.
- That's a shame.
Both my parents are dead.
It's just Paige.
She's my family now.
And what kind of work do you do, Leo?
I just opened up my own
recording studio downtown.
Paige actually convinced me
to turn it into a business.
- I did?
- Yeah.
Isn't that sort of a dying field?
No, I just mean, can't people record
things on their computers at home
- and they sound just as good?
- Ryan.
- What?
- Look, the records that I like,
they have life and warmth and soul.
Like the slapback on Scotty
Moore's guitar on Mystery Train.
Look, you're not gonna get
that in your computer.
You're gonna want a live room,
you're gonna want to bounce to tape.
You're gonna want real musicians
in a room, vibing off of each other.
You...
I guess, to answer your question,
it may be a dying field
and you can record
high-quality stuff at home.
But, I mean, come on, you can't get
the Sun Sessions on your laptop.
I heard everyone is
gonna be here tonight.
This kind of thing might be a
little too much for Paige.
No, I'm good here, actually.
Isn't that Diane Chain?
Yeah, we don't really
hang out any more.
God, you have been away a long time.
Oh, my God!
Good luck, man.
- Hi!
- Hi.
Sorry. Leo, these are my
friends from high school.
This is Shana, Carrie, Lizbet.
Hi.
What about me?
I don't get an introduction?
- Hi.
- Sorry, this is...
- Jeremy.
It's been a long time.
Has it?
It doesn't seem like it.
You haven't changed a bit.
I'm not sure if she mentioned it. I'm Leo.
- Hi.
- Paige's husband.
Right. I'm gonna grab a drink.
You guys want anything?
- Disaronno sour?
- I'll have a blueberry mojito.
Really?
Yes, I remember.
Oh, my God, Paige. Do you remember
when we were in the ninth grade,
and we were getting ready
for the Christmas dance,
we were curling your hair...
We ended up burning off half your hair.
I totally remember that!
And didn't I wind up having to
wear a beret to the dance?
No, no, no, that was the...
It was like she was some
sweater-set wearing,
mojito-drinking sorority girl.
Like a Stepford wife?
Yeah, basically. She was even flirting
with Jeremy right in front of me.
- Ex-fiancé Jeremy?
- No,no.No.
In her mind, it's current fiance Jeremy.
Which is why it was
probably pretty annoying
to have her stranger husband
cock-block her all night.
That is a lot to get my mind around.
So, what turns her on?
- Paige?
- No, her mother.
Yes, Paige.
Like, in bed?
Oh, my God, Leo.
What? It's private. It's...
I don't know. It's... It's kind of
a between-me-and-her kind of thing.
Hey, I'm not gonna judge.
She likes being tickled.
Seriously?
Thought you weren't gonna judge.
I'm not. I'm just... I...
I don't care if you're into kink.
It's not like that.
It just breaks her down
when she's stuck in her head.
Okay. You should give that a shot.
- Seriously?
- Yeah. What do you have to lose?
- Hey, Lisa.
- Hey.
Paige?
Because I've been dealing with these
people forever and I know they have...
Something importantjust popped up.
I'm gonna call you right back. Okay.
- Hi.
Please.
So, you remember that time at the lake,
when you told me you'd always
have my back, no matter what?
- The night in the boathouse.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
So, can you please tell me
what went down with us?
Only you, Paige, can dump a guy,
then come back and demand answers.
So I dumped you?
A cruel, hard, pre-wedding dumping.
Why?
Well, that's a question
that I and all of my friends
and the two rebound girls, yeah,
we'd all love an answer to.
Come on, seriously.
I must have had some kind of reason.
You...
You... You changed.
You talked differently,
you dressed differently.
You weren't sure about
law school any more.
And you definitely weren't sure
about me any more.
- Did I give you your ring back?
- Yeah, you did.
Who has that now?
No one yet.
But I've been with Rose.
You remember? From Gwen's class.
I've been with Rose
for about a year now.
I couldn't wait forever, Paige.
You couldn't have anticipated
that I'd have a brain trauma
and forget our break-up
and come waltzing into your office
demanding answers?
What's wrong with you?
I'm sorry. I'm gonna let
you go back to work.
Sure.
- Sorry.
- I'm sorry.
I was not expecting that.
Habit, I guess.
I honestly didn't even know where
I was headed until I found myself here.
It just seems so ridiculous to me
that I shut everyone out for five years.
It just doesn't feel right.
Hey.
- Hey.
- How was your day?
It was fine.
I'm just happy to be home with you.
Sorry about the mess here.
No problem.
- What, are you collaging?
- Do I collage?
No, not that I remember.
No, you know, I was just so inspired
just seeing everybody last night.
To collage?
All those memories just
came flooding back to me,
so I thought I'd make a timeline,
you know, of my life.
That's... That's great.
That's a great idea.
Yeah.
I kind of rummaged through some
of your stuff. I hope you don't mind.
It's fine. It's fine. What's mine is yours.
I even have a certificate
from the State of Illinois to prove it.
Yes, I found that. It's in the lost years.
See, I started over here.
I found some family photos,
me when I was little, stuff like that.
That was easy to put into chronological
order because I remember that stuff.
- That's good, right?
- Yeah, yeah. I guess so.
But what I've been trying to do
is pinpoint the last memory I had
before everything just went blank.
How's that going?
I think I was at the Macaroni Grill,
and I was asking them if they had
those special toasted ravioli.
And I don't remember the answer.
That's it, that's all, that's my last
memory before I woke up in a hospital.
No. How are we ever gonna know
if they had toasted ravioli?
God, this is not happening.
- It's okay.
- This is not happening.
Okay? No, no, no, no,
please don't do that.
- Come on.
- What...
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Was that...
That was one of our things?
- Yeah, kind of. It...
- I'm sorry...
No. You don't have to say it.
You don't. I get it. It'll all come back.
We just have to keep
doing what we're doing,
let you fall back into your life.
It'll all sort itself out.
Yeah.
About a dozen downtown
businesses were boarded up...
Glass littered sidewalks,
following two nights of protests
-over the police shooting of an...
- Hey.
There were few people on the street.
I think I'm ready to see my studio now.
- Will you show it to me?
- Yeah.
Come on.
This is the first studio
you've ever had to yourself.
It's a cool space, huh?
You weren't sure you
liked it at first, though.
Until you had this idea
to burn some smudge stick
that you bought from some
guy on the corner of Diversey.
We lit this thing and we
started waving it around
until we realized that it was
just some old pieces of lettuce.
So, we're waving around
burning lettuce. I don't know.
But it must've done the trick, though,
'cause after that,
I couldn't get you out of here.
You would come in and crank your music,
and you'd get lost in a project,
and I'd have to come and
remind you that it was nighttime.
This is one of your pieces
for the Tribune Tower series.
What is it supposed to be?
I'm not sure if you even knew yet.
But come here.
I...
Here, just help it figure out
what it wants to be.
Okay.
I don't...
I don't really know how to use this thing.
Sure you do. Wait, hold on.
That's better. Come on.
Just try it. It might be fun.
Can you just turn
down the music, please?
I swear you used to listen to it
so much louder than this.
I never could understand how
you would just be able to focus...
I have a clinically bad, goddamn headache!
Please turn down the music!
I'm trying to help you!
But I am not your punching bag.
We don't speak to each other like this.
This is hard for me, too, Paige.
Paige?
Yeah?
- Hey.
I passed by that little Portuguese bakery
that you love on the way home,
and I got us some...
- ls somebody here?
- Yeah.
- Leo.
- Hey.
My sister's just up to her
eyeballs with this wedding stuff,
and we've got the
engagement party coming up.
And we all thought Paige could
come home and help her out.
It just seems like the right thing
to do, to be there for Gwen.
Okay. But what about your life here?
What about all the work
that you haven't finished?
I talked to the people at the Tribune.
And they were really understanding
about the accident,
and Dad's gonna loan me the money
to pay back their advance, so...
I don't know. I just... I can't do it.
You just come out when
you're ready, honey.
Okay, thanks, Dad.
I'm sorry. It's just until after the wedding.
I just want you to be careful, okay?
Well, I'm not joining a cult.
I'm just going to stay with my family.
- I know, but...
- But what?
Can I at least give you an awkward hug?
- So, how are you feeling?
- I feel fine.
Yeah? No dizziness,
disorientation, sleepiness?
- Nope.
- Great.
Well, I'm very happy,
and your CT scan looks excellent.
What a relief. Well...
So, your memory recall, anything?
- Not really.
- No, huh?
That's not normal, is it?
Listen, when it comes to the brain,
nothing is normal,
because no two brain
injuries are the same.
Paige seems perfectly herself again.
It's wonderful.
Mrs. Thornton, could I just talk to
Paige alone for a moment, please?
It's okay, Mom. I'm... I'm good.
All right.
Thanks.
Paige, do you want to
regain your memory?
Yes.
Because some patients fear
that when their memory comes back,
so will the memory of the trauma,
but mercifully that's rarely the case.
Oh, no, that's not it. I'm... I'm...
I'm not afraid of the accident.
So, what are you afraid of?
I guess I just... I don't know. It's...
I mean, what if I don't
like the life that I had?
Or what if I like it too much?
I...
I just don't know.
I only did one psych rotation,
so this may be terrible advice.
But I think you have
to try and fill the holes.
You can still decide
you want a different life,
but if you don't at least
open yourself up to remembering,
I'm afraid you're gonna live
in fear of your own past.
Hey. I'm here.
These guys are?
Knife Skillz, With a Z.
Right.
Okay, Mikey, sounds amazing.
Let's just go for it.
I am going for it.
The bass line is one note.
- Just one note.
- Okay, cool.
Take two.
You look different.
Yeah. Going for a Kanye kind of thing.
I'm gonna say more Michael Bublé,
but, whatever, it's still good.
So... I'm gonna be in
and out for a while.
Sounds really good, Mikey.
Let's just take it from the top
or the middle or wherever.
You know what? People come
here to work with you, okay?
I mean, I'm doing my best,
but you gotta be here.
I know.
But if Paige is in Lake
Forest with her family,
that's where I gotta be.
I gotta make my wife
fall in love with me again.
- You found each other.
- Hi!
- Hi.
- Let's see it.
It's good to see you.
All right, take it easy.
- The countdown's on, man.
- Hey, man.
One week left of your former life.
How you feeling?
I feel pretty good, actually.
I mean, I do get a little dizzy
if I think about it for too long, but...
What?
No, honey, it's like a good dizzy. It's like...
It's like panic or excitement.
Well, panic and excitement are different.
- Honey, there's gonna be 400 people there.
- Right.
Hey, do you also have
a little tingling in your fingers?
Yeah. Is that bad?
Do you listen to Radiohead?
Thom Yorke,
he talks about dizzy spells all the time.
He says when his fingers tingle,
that's how he knows
that he's creating something genius.
And then he gets so amped up
playing that he almost passes out.
Ryan, it sounds to me like
you're on the verge of genius.
- That's cool, man.
- Cheers.
Ryan, I have someone
I want you to meet.
- Mom, you listen to Radiohead?
- Yeah. Why wouldn't I?
So, is that true?
Paige?
Hey, Leo.
- What?
- Your hair.
It looks so different.
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you.
Okay, look, so I've been
thinking about something.
- Okay.
- What's your favorite book?
- It's probably not what you remember.
- That's fine. That's not the point.
Okay. The Beach House by James Patterson.
- No, really?
- Yeah.
Okay. The Beach House.
Okay, if it was great, you probably
loaned it to somebody, right?
Yeah. Gwen, I think.
Okay, and you probably said to yourself,
God, I wish I was the person
that hadn't read it,
"so that I could experience it all over again."
Yeah, I guess so.
That's how I think we should look at this.
What?
You can't remember how we met.
And you can't remember
how we fell in love.
And in a way, yeah, that sucks.
But it was the greatest time of my life.
I just thought how cool it would be
to get to experience it all over again.
Like reading your favorite book
for the first time.
- Exactly.
- Got you.
Which is why I want to
ask you out on a date.
A date?
Like two people that are just
meeting for the first time.
Jeremy...
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Well, I don't know. I mean, you know,
we've got the wedding coming up.
But if we go out before then,
you might still be able
to take me as your date.
I can't promise anything,
but I'll put in a good word for you.
All right.
- Yeah?
- A date.
So, I have an idea, but it
involves going into the city.
- You okay with that?
- Yeah, that's fine.
I just have to be back
by 10:00 in the morning.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
First date and you're already
inviting yourself to stay the night?
I'm just a little scandalized is all.
- No, I just meant...
- Don't worry. I'll have you back tonight.
If you wanna stay the night, that's...
I mean, it's... If you want...
You wanna just see how it goes? All right.
Should we get out?
We don't have to.
Is this the part of the
date where I find out
you're not actually my husband
but some crazy stalker,
and you're gonna strangle me
with my purse?
No. This is the exact parking spot
where we first met.
I'm gonna take you on
a little retrospective of us.
That is so good.
You ready for dessert?
Dessert?
- We just had waffles.
- This is dinner.
These are dessert.
Well, how do you know
what flavors they all are?
It's like a chocolate Russian roulette.
It's part of the fun.
We'd be surprised by the ones
we liked and the ones we didn't.
Okay.
And...
- You don't like it?
- I do not like that one.
Here. Try this one.
I think you'd like this one.
- Told you.
- Okay.
Your turn.
Are we going shot for shot?
Wait till you try their hot chocolate.
We would come here
whenever it snowed.
Are you trying to make me diabetic
or just fat?
No, I...
You got a... It's still in your hair.
So, we come down here at night
and look at the lake?
That's not exactly what we do.
I... I'm not...
- I don't...
- No, no, it's not that.
We said we'd go in once a month every
month, and we haven't done April yet.
We started in July.
Why? Why would we do that?
We were at this spaghetti place, and
we had this waiter and he said he did it.
And he was, like, 80.
So we thought we could.
Yeah.
- Now, we said no wetsuits, but...
- You're serious.
...for you, I guess I'll make an exception.
All right. Turn around.
Turn around.
Okay.
- Wait. No wetsuit?
- We said no wetsuits, right?
Yeah.
Oh, no.
No,no.No,no!
Come on.
Thank you.
- Heat, heat.
- My left eyelid's frozen shut.
I can't feel my fingers.
I can't feel them.
I don't know what your
Paige did on a first date,
but with me, you're
only getting to first base.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I can do better.
My... My lips are still numb.
It's nice.
Second base, tops.
This is perfect.
Thank you for coming
out with me tonight.
I had a really nice time.
I've missed you.
I miss our life together.
I miss being with you.
I love you.
I should probably get inside.
Good night.
Hey.
Hey. I didn't know you
were gonna be here.
Were you out with Jeremy?
No.
I was with Leo.
I like him.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Are you okay?
Paige, I've never seen you like this before.
I mean, is this crying thing the new you?
Because it's bizarre.
I don't know. I don't know what's me.
I have a tattoo.
And I'm a vegetarian, too.
Look, it was just like it used to be.
It was better, actually.
Everything that I fell in love with
about Paige is still there.
You know, to you, I'm sure it seemed
like a confirmation of your love
or your marriage, right?
But to her, it probably seemed
more like a really good first date.
Exactly. Which is why
I think you've gotta wait
the requisite three days before you call.
I gotta wait three days to call
after a date with my own wife?
At least. This is a unique case. Maybe longer.
It can't be longer. I'm gonna see
her on Saturday at the wedding.
I'm telling you, it was so obvious.
Even with all this crazy shit going
on around us, we still belong together.
- Obvious to her or to you?
- To both of us.
- Paige?
- Yeah?
We have to start writing out
those place cards after we eat.
Yes.
Before you start on that,
I have a little surprise for you, Paige.
You know Ray Porter, right?
He taught constitutional
law at Northwestern.
He and I were on law review together.
We've known each other 1,000 years.
He is the dean of the law school now.
- Okay.
- And they're gonna let you back in.
What?
Well...
I didn't even apply.
I took care of it.
This is crazy.
I feel like I'm getting a
free do-over in life.
You look like you could use a drink.
I've already had several.
But you haven't had this.
All right.
I'm glad we're having a moment alone.
I haven't gotten a chance
to really talk to you, Leo.
Yeah.
Yeah, cool.
Congratulations.
- That's nice.
- Yes, it is.
I've been thinking.
And I think that it's probably time
to let us take it from here.
Take what?
Things with Paige.
Look, I know she didn't have
health insurance because
you chose to live in a certain way,
and I know you must
be drowning in debt.
But I also know a way out of this.
What's that?
Divorce her.
The bills have only just begun, Leo.
Mr. Thornton, I don't think this is
the time or the place to discuss this.
Fine. If you don't care
about losing your business,
which, clearly, you don't,
what about Paige?
What about doing what is
obviously the right thing for her?
- And you know what's right for her?
- As a matter of fact, I do.
- You're such a hypocrite.
- What did you say?
If you're such a family
man, how come I...
I never once saw you come and try
to put things back together with Paige?
You're such a coward.
Hey, can I introduce you around a little bit?
- Can't feel good to be the odd man out.
- I'm not the odd man out.
All right. If you say so. You just seem
a little creepy over here all by yourself.
I'm just waiting for Paige, man.
All right, well, best of luck with that.
You like this, right?
- I'm sorry, like what?
- Paige leaves you behind.
She goes and has this life without you,
with some guy that no one gets.
And now you get to
see her reject all that.
I mean, I like it a little bit.
Yeah?
Well, let me tell you what I like.
I like the fact that Paige told me
everything about you, Jeremy.
Okay.
She told me that when she was with you,
she would wake up at night in a panic,
thinking, "Is this all there is?"
She told you everything, huh?
Did she tell you that she threw
herself at me the other day?
Did she tell you that?
Or did she stop telling you everything
when she forgot who the hell you were?
Look, I get why you're being such a dick.
You obviously love her, and you
think you're gonna get her back.
But the thing is, she outgrew you.
What makes you think
that won't happen again?
Thank you for that advice.
I will mull it over while I'm
in bed with your wife.
Leo!
- Paige, wait!
- What the hell were you thinking?
I don't know. That's a really good question,
because I have been driving myself insane,
making a complete ass of myself!
Literally trying everything possible
to try to save what we have.
And you've been
throwing yourself at Jeremy.
- That's not fair.
- It's not fair?
I see the way you look at him.
I know,
because you used to
look at me that way.
- Leo, I...
- No, I think we need to start being realistic.
Your memory's not coming back.
The fact is that I'm still just a stranger.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
But I'm just...
I'm so tired of disappointing you.
I know.
I'm so sorry.
I'll apologize to Gwen and Ryan.
Oh, God, no, it's fine.
Wedding disasters have a way
of turning into great stories.
Eventually.
How do you look at the girl you love
and tell yourself it's time to walk away?
Leo?
I hope one day I can love
the way that you love me.
You figured it out once.
You'll do it again.
Shit.
You're here, not there.
Are you okay?
I'm done.
It's over. I give up.
No, you never give up, Leo.
No, if we were meant to be
together, we would be together.
I was just thinking about the first time
that we went to that Greek restaurant
on the corner.
There was this big banner saying
"Now Serving Soup,"
and I just started to go on and on
about all the obstacles
that the owner must have overcome
to achieve his lifelong
dream of serving soup.
And then... And when I was finished...
She didn't say anything for
a few seconds and she just...
She just sort of exhaled it.
It was almost to herself.
"I love you."
And it just hung there.
It was the first time she had said it,
and I didn't even wanna respond.
I just wanted to keep hearing it.
That was two weeks after we met.
It only took her two weeks
to fall in love with me before.
She doesn't love me.
Sign here, please.
Come here, little buddy.
Diane?
Hey.
- How are you?
- Listen...
I know it's been years.
I was away for a while.
I never had a chance to apologize.
I was just going through
a really weird time,
but your dad ended it
as soon as your mother
confronted him about us.
And I just always wanted
you to know that.
I don't mean to open old wounds, but...
I just really needed
to say that I'm sorry.
No, I'm really glad that
you said something.
You were always a really good friend.
I just wish I could've returned the favor.
The lilies were bad,
so I got sunflowers instead.
- I wanted to tell you.
- You knew?
You knew the whole time?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't talk to me.
Paige. Paige. Paige!
Hey, where have you
been all day, stranger?
Paige?
I ran into Diane Chain at the store.
That's why I left, isn't it?
Because I found out.
Mom, I barely even know who I am,
and then it turns out you're lying to me,
and you've used my accident
to rewrite the past?
I couldn't bear the thought
of losing you again.
Do you have any idea how
betrayed I feel right now?
I'm sorry, Paige.
We were happier than
we'd been in years.
- Mom!
- We finally had you back again.
- Back on your terms!
- No!
- Yes, as usual!
- Paige!
He cheated on you with my friend!
How could you stay with him?
I...
I was going to leave.
I was. I was all ready to leave.
And then one afternoon,
I was all alone in the house,
and I started looking at
all the photographs of you
and your...
And your sister.
And the house seemed
so full of all of us.
We were a family, Paige.
And I realized in that moment that
that was the most important
thing in the world for me.
And I couldn't, I couldn't,
I could not go.
So, you just wasped it away?
No.
I chose to stay with him
for all the things that he had done right
and not to leave him for the
one thing that he had done wrong.
I chose to forgive him.
Maybe Leo was right.
Maybe I can't figure out who
I am and be around all of you.
I still feel a little chilly.
I don't care what you say.
That's fine.
Paige.
- I'm sorry.
- ls everything okay?
Look, you two obviously
need to talk, so I'm just...
- Okay.
- Talk to you later.
All right, bye.
I'm... I'm sorry.
What happened?
- Can I ask you something?
- Yeah.
You can always ask me anything.
Did you know about my dad's affair?
Yeah.
I knew.
Why didn't you tell me?
There were so many
times that I almost did.
But to drive you away
from your family again?
That just felt wrong.
I wanted your love, I...
Just not like that.
I wanted to earn it.
I just don't think I can afford
to lose them right now.
So don't.
Certain parties have sought
to nullify various congressional acts,
claiming that repeated extensions
of copyright protection
constitute a perpetual copyright
of the sort the drafters of the
Constitution would have rejected.
The United States Supreme Court,
in the 2003 case of Eldred v. Ashcroft...
Thanks for lunch.
Actually, there's something
that I wanted to tell you.
Okay.
Things are over with Rose.
I ended it, Paige.
No. Why did you do that?
I thought you were getting engaged...
We were, but that was before you.
No, that was after me.
Okay, it was after you,
but it was before this you.
It was before the old you came back.
Jeremy, I'm not the old me.
I'm just me.
I'm just the me that's
trying to figure it out still.
I understand, but, whichever it is,
the old you or the new you, I don't care.
I know you remember what we
were like together. I know you do.
- This is our chance to get that back.
- What we had was wonderful.
Those were wonderful memories,
but those were...
Those are my only memories.
Everything after you is erased.
I...
I have to discover what it's like
to be without you, on my own.
Are you sure you don't remember
breaking up with me the first time?
Why?
'Cause it sounded a
hell of a lot like that.
Let's go.
Hey. I was looking all over.
I was worried when I didn't
see you outside the library.
So...
How's that intellectual
property class going?
Actually, I wanna talk to you about that.
I've decided to leave law school.
And I'm gonna get an
apartment in the city.
It's happening all over again, isn't it?
Damn it, Paige.
I've made a lot of mistakes.
Dad, this isn't about you
or anything you've done.
This is about me,
who I want to be, who I am.
Just tell me what to say,
so I don't lose you again.
You won't.
A moment of impact.
A moment of impact
whose potential for change
has ripple effects far beyond
what we can predict,
sending some particles
crashing together
making them closer than before,
while sending others spinning
off into great ventures
landing where you never
thought you'd find them.
You see, that's the thing
about moments like these.
You can't,
no matter how hard you try,
control how they're gonna affect you.
You just gotta let the colliding
particles land where they may
and wait until the next collision.
I vow to help you love life,
to always hold you with tenderness,
and to have the patience
that love demands.
To speak when words are needed
and to share the silence when they're not.
To agree to disagree on red velvet cake.
And to live within the warmth of
your heart and always call it home.
Hi.
I hope you didn't come all the way
into the city for hot chocolate.
Actually, I moved back
here six months ago.
I'm over in Rogers Park.
Really? That... That's great.
I'm actually back at the Art Institute.
What? Are you kidding me?
That's amazing.
Yeah. I mean, I'm sitting
in on a few classes,
and it's crazy what my hands remember
that my, you know, that my mind forgot.
Yeah.
So, thank you.
I didn't do anything.
You did everything.
You accepted me for who I am,
and not for what you wanted me to be.
I just wanted you to be happy.
That's all.
Isn't there some Cuban
place around here
where we used to go
when this place was closed?
Yeah. It's... Wait. You remember?
No, no.
I wish.
No, the memory stuff
hasn't come back, but I've...
Sonia and I have been
hanging out a little bit,
and I've been asking her about us.
Really? And what has she been saying?
That she doesn't think
you're seeing anyone right now.
She just happens to be right.
You? Are you seeing anyone?
That's good.
So, do you wanna
go to the Cuban place?
With me?
Okay.
What would you say to trying someplace
that we haven't been to before?
Someplace new?
I'd like that.
After you.