Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Thank you, Alice.
You've been a big help.
I wish I could have tea
with everyone.
I really wish I could.
Tea is for grownups,
dear.
But, Mother,
when will I be grown up?
Oh, be patient, Alice.
Teatime for you
will come soon enough.
Now, why don't you
go outside and keep
your sister company?
Yes, Mother.
Okay.
You know,
I really do wish
you'd tell me,
just what good is a book
without any pictures?
It looks so dull.
I mean, it really does.
You'll understand soon enough,
when you grow up.
Look, I'm already
seven and a half.
I think
that's quite grown up.
And I really do wish
you'd stop talking to me
as though I was a child.
But you are
still a child, Alice.
You can't really think
that you're a grownup.
Yes, I do. Almost.
I mean, just how on Earth
am I supposed to know
when I'm grown up or not?
Would you mind
telling me that?
There are a lot of ways
to know that.
Well, then tell me.
At least a hint.
Well, for one thing,
you have to be much taller
to be grown up.
And you won't cry as much.
You are a bit
of a crybaby.
I am not.
I don't cry much at all.
Hardly ever.
Well, when you've grown up,
you'll cry much less
than you do now.
And one of the best ways
to know if you've grown up
is when Mother asks you
to join the rest
of the grownups for tea.
Dinah, dear,
you think I'm grown up,
don't you?
Oh, dear! Oh, dear!
I shall be too late.
Mr. Rabbit!
Oh, my ears and whiskers,
how late it's getting!
Mr. Rabbit!
Wait! Wait!
That's strange.
I wonder how many there are.
How am I ever
gonna get home?
I can't imagine
who could fit through there.
Unless it was for a mouse.
This must fit
that little door.
Oh, how beautiful.
This must surely
be the way home.
I can't get through.
It's all very well
to say, "Drink Me."
I'll look first and see
whether it's marked poison
or not.
Mmm.
Oh.
Oh, I... I feel so strange.
Oh, my.
Oh.
What's happening to me?
I'm shrinking!
I'm so small.
So very small.
But now, at least,
I'm the right size
for going through
the little door.
Oh, how stupid!
How really stupid!
I've forgotten the key
way up on top of that table.
Come on now, Alice,
there's no use
starting to cry.
Stop it this moment.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Now, what's this?
"Eat me."
That's certainly
a strange thing
to write on a cake.
But I will eat it.
Perhaps it'll make me
grow bigger.
And If it makes me
grow bigger,
then I can reach the key.
But if it makes me
grow a little smaller,
then I can creep
under the door.
Bigger or smaller?
Which way?
Oh, I think
I'm staying the same size.
Oh.
Oh, something is happening.
Curiouser and curiouser.
Ooh.
Now I'm opening up
like a telescope.
Ooh. Goodbye, feet!
I'm so big, now I'll never
get through that little door.
I wanna go home.
Oh, the Duchess,
the Duchess!
Won't she be savage
if I kept her waiting?
If you please, sir.
Sir, Rabbit!
What's happening now?
Ooh.
It's the fan
that's making me shrink!
Oh, that was a narrow escape.
Oh, now I've fallen
into the sea.
But this isn't the sea.
These are my tears
when I was nine feet tall!
Oh, I wish
I hadn't cried so much.
I should be
punished for it now,
for being drowned
in my own tears.
Won't that be a queer thing?
However, everything's
been queer today.
What is that?
It must be a walrus
or a hippopotamus!
For goodness' sake,
stop crying.
Stop crying!
Don't cry anymore!
Sir?
Me?
Do you know
the way out of here?
I'm a stranger here myself.
Mouse, do you know
the way out?
Mouse, don't you
understand English?
What?
Are you French?
That means, "Where's my cat?"
You know.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
I quite forgot
you don't like cats.
Our family has
always hated cats.
Nasty, low, vulgar things.
Don't ever let me
hear that name again!
I won't. I promise.
Are you afraid of dogs?
There's a nice old terrier
who kills all the rats.
Oh! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry!
I won't mention
those creatures again!
All right. Come on.
Let's go to shore
and I'll tell you
why I hate cats and dogs.
That's a very good idea.
Excellent, Sir Mouse.
# I hate dogs
and I hate cats #
# I'm also not
too fond of bats #
# I'm a helpless
little fellow #
# Consequently
rather yellow #
# Now, you may think
that dogs are sweet #
# Since they love to
snuggle at your feet #
# But to me
they're oh, so large #
# That I tremble
when they charge #
# Now, certain words
like "big" and "small" #
# Mean what?
# Would you
please tell me? #
# To me all cats
are 10 feet tall #
# So I worry
when they smell me #
# I run from owls
I hide from hawks #
# I scurry from
whatever squawks #
# I'm a coward
# From my whiskers
to my spats #
# I hate dogs
and cats! #
# Now, certain words
like "big" and "small" #
# Mean what?
# Would you
please tell me? #
# To me all cats
are 10 feet tall #
# So I worry
when they smell me #
# I run from owls
I hide from hawks #
# I scurry from
whatever squawks #
# I'm a coward
# From my whiskers
to my spats! #
# But I tell you straight
# That I really hate
# Owls, dogs, hawks, bats!
# I hate dogs and cats! #
Hey,
what are you running for?
Wait a minute.
Just what is
going on around here?
Are you all crazy?
Won't anybody answer me?
Now, wait a minute! Hey!
Now I know what it means
to act like animals!
Somebody should
teach you all proper manners.
The Duchess!
Oh, my dear paws!
Oh, my fur
and whiskers.
She'll have me executed
as sure as ferrets
are ferrets.
And where on Earth
did I drop my fan
and gloves?
I know, Mr. Rabbit.
I had them,
but I seem to have
lost them.
Mary Ann, what are you
doing out here?
You go home this moment
and... and fetch me a pair
of gloves and fan.
Quick now, Mary Ann!
He mistook me
for his housemaid.
How surprised he'll be
when he finds out
who I am really.
But I'd better find
his fan and gloves
and bring them
back to him if I can.
It seems so silly
to be running errands
for a rabbit.
I suppose Dinah will be
giving me orders next.
Like, "Alice,
come here directly
and watch this mouse hole
until I get back."
There's the fan and gloves.
I know something interesting
is sure to happen
whenever I eat
or drink anything.
So I'll just see
what this bottle does.
Now, that's quite enough.
I hope I won't grow
any more.
As it is,
I'm sure I won't be able
to get through the door.
I wish I hadn't
drunk so much.
Mary Ann! Mary Ann!
Fetch me my gloves
this moment!
Pat! Pat!
Where are you?
Back here
digging for apples,
Your Honor.
Digging for apples,
indeed!
Come and get me
out of here!
Your Honor,
what happened? Here.
Pat! Pat!
Wha-What's that in the window?
I-I-I-It's an arm,
Your Honor.
An arm?
You goose!
Did you ever see
an arm that size?
It fills the whole window.
It sure does, Your Honor,
but... but it's an arm anyway.
Yeah, well,
at any rate,
it has no business there.
You... You go
and take it away.
Oh, I don't like this at all,
Your Honor.
I... I don't like it at all.
Bill! Bill!
Come out here and help!
And bring the ladder!
Quick, Bill!
I got it.
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
Come on, bring it here.
Here,
tell him what to do.
Get up on the roof.
Oh, my goodness.
Hurry, Bill.
Do you think
the roof will hold him?
I hope so!
Bill!
Oh, my goodness.
Bill, go down the chimney!
That's a good idea,
Your Honor.
Down the chimney, Billy!
Down the chimney!
Bill's got to go down
the chimney, does he?
I think I can
take care of that.
Watch your step, Bill!
Down the chimney, Bill.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
That's for Bill.
There goes Bill.
Goodbye, Bill!
I wonder what
they're gonna do next.
You'd better
not do that again.
They're such little cakes.
If I eat one,
they're sure to make
some change in my size.
And since it can't possibly
make me grow larger.
Mary Ann!
Mary Ann! Come back here!
Come back here,
Mary Ann! You hear me?
Come back here!
Mary Ann! Stop running!
Come back!
Who are you?
I hardly know, sir.
I knew who I was
when I got up this morning,
but I keep changing sizes.
And I'm afraid
I'll never find
my way home again.
Explain yourself.
I can't, sir.
Because I'm not myself,
you see?
No, I don't see.
Well, being so many sizes
in one day
is very confusing
to a little girl.
No, it isn't.
Well, perhaps
you haven't found it so yet.
But when you have to
turn into a chrysalis
and then a butterfly,
you'll feel a little bit queer
then, won't you?
Not a bit.
Well, it would feel
very queer to me.
You? Who are you?
Well, I think
you ought to tell me
who you are first.
Why?
Well, I don't know exactly.
Besides, I think
you're very rude.
Goodbye!
Wait! Wait!
I've got something
very important to say to you.
What?
Keep your temper.
Is that all
you have to say to me?
Well, no.
I was also curious
about your earlier remark.
So you think
you've changed, do you?
I definitely have.
In fact,
I think I've actually
grown up quite a bit.
But I can't quite remember.
Why not?
Well, there are
a lot of things.
Oh, like
when I tried to recite
one of my favorite poems,
it came out all wrong.
Well, try You Are Old,
Father William,
and see
how that comes out.
Do you know that poem?
Of course.
Let me see. It starts...
"You...
"You..."
Wait, let me help you.
# "You are old,
Father William,"
the young man said #
# "And your hair
has become very white #
# "And yet you incessantly
stand on your head #
# "Do you think,
at your age, it is right?" #
# "In my youth,"
Father William
replied to his son #
# "I feared
it might injure the brain #
# "But now that
I'm perfectly sure
I have none #
# "Why, I do it again
and again" #
# "You are old,"
said the youth #
# "As I mentioned before,
and have grown
most uncommonly fat #
# "Yet you turned
a back-somersault
in at the door #
# "Pray,
what is the reason
for that?" #
# "You are old,"
said the youth #
# "And your jaws are too weak
for anything
tougher than suet #
# "Yet you finished the goose
with the bones and the beak #
# "Pray,
how did you manage
to do it?" #
# "You are old,"
said the youth #
# "One would hardly suppose
that your eye
was as steady as ever #
# "Yet you balanced
an eel on the end
of your nose #
# "What made you
so awfully clever?" #
# "You have asked me
three questions
Now, that is enough" #
# Said his father,
"Don't give yourself airs! #
# "Do you think I can listen
all day to such stuff? #
# "Be off, boy!
# "Or I'll kick you
downstairs #
downstairs" #
That was excellent.
Now, what size do you
want to be, little girl?
Well, I should like to be
a little larger, sir.
This is such
a wretched height to be,
you know.
Oh? It happens to be
a very good height indeed,
since it also happens
to be exactly my height.
I'm terribly sorry.
I didn't mean it
as an insult.
Mr. Caterpillar,
where are you?
Why, he's disappeared.
He just
absolutely disappeared.
Surely someone here
can tell me
the way to go home.
It's for the Duchess.
It's an invitation
from the Queen
to play croquet.
There's no use in ringing,
because I'm on the same side
of the gate as you are.
Then how am I
supposed to get in?
Well, I don't know
about you,
but as for me,
I'm going to sit here
until tomorrow
or the next day, maybe.
Well, I'm not.
Oh, there's certainly
too much pepper in that soup.
Not in my soup.
Oh, no.
Will you please be careful?
If everybody minded
their own business,
this world would go around
a lot faster than it does.
Which would not
be an advantage,
if you ask me.
I mean, you see,
the Earth takes 24 hours
to turn around its axis.
Speaking of axes,
chop off her nose.
You are acting
very hateful to that baby.
Am I?
Well, my dear.
# There's something
to say for hatred #
# For rudeness
and for spite #
# Oh, no, my friend,
we can't pretend #
# That everything's
sweetness and light #
# There's something
to say for trouble #
# For nastiness
and gloom #
# Just try to be cheerful
# And you'll get an earful
of your impending doom #
# This world
is not a paradise #
# lf, indeed, ooh, ooh,
it ever was #
# It's a vale of tears
and so, my dears #
# Throw out the chaff?
Don't make me laugh #
# There's something
to say for misery #
# For suffering
and pain #
# Down at the bank,
now, let's be frank #
# They only care for gain
# There's something to say
for frowning #
# Why must we always smile?
# Forget all your dreams,
resort to schemes #
# And in just a little while
# The best-laid plans
of mice and men #
# Will all come
crashing down again #
# And we'll all
despise each other #
# In the grandest style #
Is the baby all right?
You wanna hold him
for a while?
Here.
I have to get ready.
I'm playing croquet
with the Queen.
If I don't take
this baby away with me,
they're sure to kill it.
Now, look, little baby,
if you're going
to turn into a pig,
then I'll have nothing more
to do with you.
Oh, well,
if it had grown up,
it would have made
a dreadfully ugly child.
But maybe
a rather handsome pig,
I suppose.
Excuse me, Cheshire Cat.
Would you tell me please
which way I ought
to go from here?
That depends a good deal
on where you wanna get to.
Home.
I need to get home.
I know my mother's
already begun to miss me.
Oh, and my cat, Dinah,
must be very hungry.
Home?
Home, is it?
Well, you listen closely,
little girl.
# There's no way home
# from this strange land
# Don't even try
to understand #
# You're lost in time
# without a trace
# Resign yourself
to your disgrace #
# Somehow you've strayed
# and lost your way
# And now there'll be
# No time to play
# No time for joy
# No time for friends
# Not even time
# to make amends
# You are too naive
# if you do believe
# Life is innocent laughter
and fun #
# There are things to fear
# So you see, my dear
# Your adventures
# have only begun
# The world's immense
# but sad to say
# It makes no sense
# in any way
# So what care I
# if you should cry?
# There's no way
# home #
I think you're a mean,
old cat.
There must be a way home
and I'll find it!
Where are you going?
That way.
Maybe I'll meet someone
kind enough to help me.
Oh.
Well, in that direction,
there's a Hatter,
and in that direction,
there's a March Hare.
Visit either you like.
They're both mad.
But I don't wanna
visit mad people.
Well, you can't help that.
We're all mad here.
I mean, I'm mad.
You're mad. We're all mad.
Meow, baby.
Well, a head without a cat
is the most curious thing
I've ever seen
in my whole life.
Oh, goody, I'm just in time
for a tea party.
May I introduce myself?
No, you may not.
But aren't introductions
proper at a tea party?
My dear child,
if you want an introduction,
go and get yourself
an orchestra.
They'll give you a good
four-bar introduction.
Or probably
an eight-bar introduction.
I just wanted to
give you my name.
Why, have you
finished with it?
Did you hear that,
Mr. Hare?
She wants to
give us her name.
That is ridiculous.
Awfully.
We already
have names.
We certainly
don't need hers.
Yes.
May I sit down?
No room! No room!
No room!
There's plenty of room!
There are at least
nine empty chairs.
Of course there are.
We didn't say
there aren't any chairs.
We said
there wasn't any room.
Yeah, and there
certainly isn't, you know.
We are here
in the great outdoors.
Of course!
And there are certainly
no rooms here.
Right.
There are a few
in the house.
Would you like some wine?
I don't think
I should drink wine.
I'm too young.
Good. There isn't
any anyway.
Then it wasn't
very nice of you to offer it.
And it wasn't
very nice of you
to sit down
without being invited!
I didn't know
it was your table!
It's set for more than three.
You know,
your hair wants cutting.
You should learn
not to make personal remarks.
It's very rude.
Ooh.
Why is a raven
like a writing desk?
I give up. Why is a raven
I haven't
the vaguest idea.
Then why did you
ask the question?
Because I was hoping
for an intelligent answer!
If I'd known the answer,
I wouldn't have
asked the question, would I?
Oh, you're hopeless.
Incidentally, how did you
become a March Hare?
Well, actually,
I started out
being a January Hare,
and then I worked
my way up.
No, I didn't mean that.
Well, then you should say
what you mean!
Quite!
I do.
At least, I mean what I say
and that's the same thing.
It isn't
the same thing at all.
I mean,
you might just as well say
"I see what I eat,"
is the same as
"I, I eat what I see."
I give up.
Fresh cup. Move down.
Whoop-de-doo.
Who's the stuffed animal?
I am not
a stuffed animal.
Really?
Not since dinner
last night.
I am a dormouse.
What do you mean,
"door mouse"?
You look like
a plain mouse to me.
And you look like
a plain little girl to me.
And if you think
that there's only
one kind of a mouse,
you have another
"think" coming.
Quite!
Do you wanna
take it right now?
Take what right now?
Your other "think."
You have one coming,
you know.
No, I... I'm not
a church mouse...
No.
...because I'm
too wealthy.
Of course!
I'm not a field mouse,
and I'm not a...
Well, I'm...
By the way,
what time is it?
Time? Time?
The time now is,
let me see.
The time is precisely 7:27.
That can't possibly
be right.
It seems to me it was 7:27
about two hours ago.
Young lady,
are you contradicting me?
I am known
as a stickler for accuracy.
A stickler? You are?
Yes, a stickler.
When people round here
want accuracy,
they call me in
and I stickle.
That's what sticklers
are supposed to do,
isn't that right?
But are you sure
your watch is running?
Oh, of course
it isn't running.
It's sitting here
quite quietly in my hand.
Besides, it could hardly run,
it has no moving parts.
No moving parts?
Correct.
But it's absolutely
correct twice a day.
Enough of this folderol!
Enough of this persiflage.
Enough of this badinage.
Enough of this
tomfoolery.
Enough of this banter.
Enough of this
saying "enough."
Oh, every tea party
should have a little music.
Of course.
Young lady,
would you like
to sing with us?
That might be very nice.
But what shall we sing?
Do you know
Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star?
Yes, I do.
# Twinkle, twinkle,
little star #
# How I wonder
what you are #
No, no, no, no.
That won't do at all.
I prefer,
"Twinkle, twinkle, little bat,
how I wonder what you're at."
How about,
# Twinkle, twinkle,
little skunk #
# How I wonder
if you're drunk #
"Twinkle, twinkle,
little ants.
"You do look strange
without your pants."
I must admit,
you three do make me laugh.
Now, that's a very good idea
for a song.
# Laugh at every
single thing we do #
# Just laugh
# And we shall all
perform for you #
# Just smile
and tensions will unwind #
# And you'll find
that your mind #
# Takes a kinder view
# Laugh
# yes, even when your skies
are gray #
# Just laugh
# And troubles
seem to float away #
# You'll find
it's very true, my dears #
# Through the years
that your tears #
# And your fears will fly
# Oh, there are times
when crying #
# Seems the thing to do
# But keep on trying
# Till your dreams
come true #
# Your heart
# I'm sure knows
what is best for you #
# So laugh, little girl
# Just laugh #
Such a lovely song.
Thank you,
I, I wrote it myself.
Now, how would you
like to tell us a story?
I'm afraid
I don't know one.
Then the Dormouse shall.
The Dormouse will.
Wake up!
Come on!
Come on. Come along.
Wake up!
La, la, la, wake up!
You've got to tell a story!
Wake up!
Tell a story.
Dormouse!
You're going to tell
a story for the little...
Wake up. Dormouse,
we want to hear a story.
You're going to love it.
Come on.
Time to wake up now.
Come on. Wake up.
Wake up. Come on, now.
Tell us a story!
Time to make a story.
Story.
Going to tell a story.
We need to tell a story.
Wake up.
Stop it! Stop it!
It doesn't matter
if anyone tells us
a story or not.
Well, that just shows you
how much you know. Hmm.
Yeah. At teatime,
everyone should tell a story.
Well, now that he is awake,
a story would be nice.
Once upon a time, there were
three little sisters
named Elsie, Lacie and Tillie
and they lived
at the bottom of a well.
But what did they live on?
They lived on treacle.
Molasses to you.
But why did they live
at the bottom of a well?
It was a treacle well.
There's no such thing.
Oh. Oh!
If you can't
keep a civil tongue,
why don't you finish
the story yourself?
No, please, go on.
Well,
these three little sisters,
they were learning
how to draw, you know.
And what did they draw?
Treacle!
I want a fresh cup.
Move down the table!
Here we go round
the table!
But I don't understand.
Where did they
draw the treacle from?
Well, if you can get water
from a water well,
I suppose you can get treacle
from a treacle well,
eh, stupid?
Hello, little fawn.
Don't be afraid,
I won't hurt you.
I'm so happy to find you.
You're the only normal person
I've met here.
# Why do people act
as if they're crazy? #
# Why do they behave
the way they do? #
# Don't they understand
# that the things
I've planned #
# Are dreams
that I demand #
# come true?
# Why can't they be kind
# to one another
# And see the beauty of
# the golden rule?
# Will there come a spring
# when we'll know
how to sing #
# that there are
better things to do? #
# Will there come a day
# we'll all know
how to say #
# I love you?
# I love
# you #
I wish I didn't have to go,
but I really must,
so you can find your mother
and I can find mine.
That's very curious.
However,
everything's curious today.
Excuse me, sirs.
But would you
tell me, please,
why you're painting
those roses?
Why, the fact is...
You see, miss,
this here ought to have
been a red rose bush,
and we put a white one in
by mistake.
Yes, and if the Queen
was to find out,
she'd cut our heads off,
you know.
The Queen! The Queen!
Here comes the Queen!
Who is this?
Who is what?
Oh!
Her. I don't know.
Idiot.
What is your name, child?
My name is Alice,
may it please Your Majesty.
We'll see about that.
And who are these creatures?
How should I know?
It's no business of mine.
Off with her head.
Oh, come now, now, dear,
be calm...
Did you hear me?
Off with her head!
Nonsense!
Nonsense?
Just for that,
off with her head
in small increments.
Oh, no, no.
Come now, dear.
She's only a child.
Did you think I was
under the impression
she was an alligator
or a rutabaga?
Of course she's a child,
and a remarkably rude one.
And if there's one thing
I cannot stand,
it's insubordination
and impertinence.
That's two things,
Your Majesty.
What? Laughing
at such effrontery!
You stop it.
Stop it right now!
Ow! Ooh! Ow! Oh!
Oh, off with their heads, too!
My dear, you must not
excite yourself, really.
# When there are people
who annoy you #
# Or seem determined
to destroy you #
# There's just one thing
that must be done #
# Off with their heads!
Oh, that's rather drastic,
isn't it, dear?
# When there are people
who deceive you #
# Or have the nerve
to not believe you #
# There's one response
that's rather fun #
# Off with their heads!
What about
the population?
# Firm
# You must be absolutely firm
when required #
I'm always firm,
dear, always.
# Squirm
# That's what they'll do
when they perceive
they've been fired #
# Or worse
# Never mind negotiation
# You will find
to rule your nation #
# All you need
to keep your slaves
under their beds #
# Is just to flounce about
and shout #
# Off with their heads!
You make it all
sound so simple.
It is simple, my dear.
They're all simple-minded.
Off with their heads.
# Firm
Yes, of course, dear.
# You must be absolutely firm
when required #
I'm going to try
to be firm about it.
Yes, darling.
# Squirm
# That's what they'll do
when they perceive
they've been fired #
Don't you...
# Or worse
# Never mind negotiation
# You will find
to rule your nation #
# All you need
to keep your slaves
under their beds #
# Is just to flounce about
and shout #
# Off with their heads! #
I suppose you're right,
as usual.
I am always right,
my dear.
It is simply...
Didn't I tell you this morning
that heads would roll?
Yes, indeed,
you did, dear.
But, you know,
it's an extraordinary thing.
Heads do not roll
as they used to.
Nowadays,
they just clump down
on the ground and stay there.
Ah!
There's that
impertinent child.
Alice, would you
come here a minute, dear?
Can you play croquet?
Why, yes, Your Majesty.
Although,
I shouldn't be able to
if I had no head.
If you think
such conditions are going
to make me change my mind,
you are quite mistaken.
Your head is as good as gone.
But since you still have it,
we might as well put it
to some sensible use.
Come along to the game.
Oh, yes.
It's a...
It's a very fine day.
The Queen seems
to be enjoying it.
She loves
to chop off heads.
Oh, well, the Queen
is very excitable.
She even ordered
the execution
of a very dear friend,
the Duchess.
What for?
Did you say,
"What a pity?"
No, I didn't.
I said, "What for?"
Oh, it was
a dreadful offense.
She boxed
the Queen's ears.
Oh, don't. Do be quiet.
The Queen will hear you.
See, what happened, you see,
was that the Duchess
came rather late
and the Queen
said to her...
What is that?
Who is doing all that
gibbering and jabbering
back there?
Oh. Oh, dear.
Meaning no disrespect,
Your Majesty.
"Gibbering and jabbering,"
you say?
Well, I... I... I was gibbering
and the... and the young lady
was jabbering.
Well, stop it!
And take your places,
all of you,
for a game of croquet.
Well, tell me, Alice,
my dear,
are you a skillful
croquet player?
Well, I do beat my sister,
at least sometimes.
Who's the best player here?
I really don't know.
Her Majesty
always manages to win.
And if anyone
ever gets close,
it's always the same thing.
"Off with their heads!"
Excuse me, Your Majesty.
I don't see any mallets.
What are we gonna use
for mallets?
These flamingoes, of course.
Of course. Of course!
And what are we to use
for croquet balls?
Guinea pigs.
He's as keen as mustard.
What are we to use
for wickets?
We do have to hit the ball
through something, don't we?
Wickets,
assume your positions.
Oh, you oaf,
you move much too slowly.
Off with his head!
It's going to be
very difficult, dear,
in that position.
They're dreadfully fond of
beheading people here,
wouldn't you say?
The great wonder is
there's anyone left here
with a head at all.
You, impertinent child,
wipe that smile
off your face.
Is that smile quite gone?
It's left
the young lady's face.
But it seems to have
reappeared elsewhere.
It's the Cheshire Cat.
Oh, hello, Cheshire Cat.
Hello. How do you
like the Queen?
Not at all.
I don't like the idea
of losing my head. Would you?
I could hardly afford that.
I say, what is that thing?
It's a friend of mine,
a Cheshire Cat.
Allow me
to introduce you.
I'd rather not,
if you don't mind.
My dear, may I introduce
another of your subjects?
No, you may not.
Ugh.
Off with his head,
whoever or whatever it is,
and off with his tail, too.
There's more than one way
to skin a cat, you know.
I'm afraid
he hasn't got a tail.
You can't behead something
that has no body.
Well, you can try.
And exactly
who is the owner
of this monster?
I think it belongs
to the Duchess, Your Majesty.
Perhaps you'd
better ask her about it.
Oh, that shouldn't
be difficult, dear.
You put her in prison.
Fetch the Duchess here
and be quick about it!
When I get home,
I'll have such
wonderful stories to tell
about kings and queens,
strange creatures
in such strange lands.
Well, as I live and breathe,
and I hope to keep it up,
if it isn't the little one.
How are you, my dear?
As well as can be expected.
And you?
Ah, you're thinking.
That makes you
forget to talk.
Well, I can't
tell you just now
the moral to that, but...
Well, I'll remember in a bit.
Perhaps, it hasn't one.
Get out of here.
Tut-tut, my child.
Everything has a moral,
if you find it.
Now, the moral to that is...
# 'Tis love, 'tis love
# 'Tis love that makes
the world go round #
Well, well,
if it isn't Her Majesty.
Well, it is.
And that being the case,
would you be good enough
to grovel?
Grovel?
Yes.
Right here on the gravel.
Well...
Do you think I'm ready
for gravel-groveling?
Now, I give you a choice.
Either you or your head
must be off, and at once!
Oh, well,
I accept your generous offer,
Your Majesty. Yes, I do.
Ta-ta.
Get out of here.
Bad riddance
to good rubbish.
With all due respect,
Your Majesty,
I think
you've got that backwards.
Oh, have I?
Bad rubbish
to good riddance.
No! It's "Good riddance
to bad rubbish."
What mockery.
And speaking of mockery,
have you met
the Mock Turtle yet?
I don't think so,
Your Majesty.
But then, I don't even know
what a mock turtle is.
Why, it's the thing
mock turtle soup is made from.
Oh, you must meet him.
Now, you just follow that path
and you'll see him.
I must attend
to some executions.
Whatever it is,
it must be trapped in there.
Oh, that poor little goat.
There, there, don't cry.
Bye, little goat.
You hurry back
to your mother.
I'm sure she misses you.
I'm sure mine does, too.
Well, thank you,
I'm glad someone
appreciates me.
Thank you,
and you hurry back
to your mother, too.
Goodbye!
Who are you?
Are you a mock turtle?
A mock turtle?
Do I look
like a mock turtle?
Can't you tell
a genuine gryphon
when you see one?
I'm so sorry,
Mr. Gryphon.
Her Majesty told me
that I'd meet
the Mock Turtle here.
Oh, you mean that
"Off with his head" queen?
She's a flibbertigibbet.
Flibbertigibbet,
flibbertigibbet.
A "flibbiti" what?
A silly ninny.
All the executions
she orders,
they never come about.
They're all her fancy.
Then why does she
even order them?
Why?
Why? Why? Why?
The eternal "why"
of a child.
Ah, but enough
of my gryphosophy.
I'll take you
to the Mock Turtle. Come on.
Everybody says "Come on."
I never was
so ordered around before
in all my life.
Never!
Come on!
Come on. Come on.
There's the Mock Turtle.
Right there.
Who are you?
I'm Alice.
Guess what his sorrow is?
Why, he must wanna go home.
I know why I'm so sad,
Mr. Mock Turtle.
I wanna go home.
I just seem to be getting
further and further away.
But why are you crying?
It's all his
morbid imagination.
He really has no sorrow.
Oh, shut up, Gryphon.
Yes, Mr. Gryphon,
please.
So, what is the matter,
Mr. Mock Turtle?
Oh, my dear.
Once I was a real turtle.
We went to school
in the sea.
My teacher
was an old turtle.
We used to call him Tortoise.
But why did you
call him Tortoise
if he was really a turtle?
We called him Tortoise
because he taught us.
Really,
you are very dull.
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself,
asking such a silly question.
Please tell me more.
Well, we had
the best of education.
Reeling and writhing,
and then
the different branches
of arithmetic.
Ambition, distraction,
uglification and derision.
Oh, shut up, Mock Turtle.
Enough about your lessons.
Why don't you sing
the little girl a song?
Well, if I'm going
to sing anything,
I suppose a song
is a good choice.
Oh, I don't know.
You could sing her
a sea chantey.
That's a thought.
I used to live
in a sea shanty.
Oh?
But I didn't
care for it much.
For the roof leaked,
as I recall.
Now, really, Mr. Turtle.
Oh, you don't
have to be so formal.
You can call me
by my first name.
And what is that?
Mock.
That's what my mother
used to call me.
"Mock," she'd say...
Well, whoever you are
and whatever you are,
absolutely nothing you say
makes any sense at all.
Oh, that's
the nicest compliment
I've ever been paid.
There's too much sense
in the world for me,
in my humble opinion.
# Please tell me, young lady,
just what is so good #
# About never once
being misunderstood #
# There's far too much
accurate communication #
# And if it continues
# I fear for the nation
# Nonsense! Nonsense!
That's what
we're terribly short of #
# Don't you love nonsense?
I'm not really sure.
Well, sort of.
# We're getting lethargic
from aiming at logic #
# Let's put a stop to that
# If you don't love nonsense
I'll knock off your hat! #
# Nonsense! Nonsense!
Simply can't do without it #
# Burn incense to nonsense
and sing us a song about it #
# Let young master Billy
be hopelessly silly
until he is blue in the face #
# We must never be grave
'Tis nonsense will save #
# The blooming human race
# Nonsense! Nonsense!
Simply can't do without it #
# Burn incense to nonsense
and sing us a song about it #
# Let young master Billy
be hopelessly silly
until he is blue in the face #
# We must never be grave
# 'Tis nonsense will save
# The blooming human race! #
Now, tell us
about your adventures.
I would tell you
my adventures beginning
from this morning,
but it's no use
going back to yesterday
because I was
a different person then.
The trial's beginning!
Come on, come on!
What trial is it?
Never mind.
Never mind. Come on.
Bye, Alice. Bye, Gryphon.
I wish
they'd get the trial done
and pass out
the refreshments.
What are they doing?
They can't have anything
to write down yet,
before the trial's begun.
They're writing down
the names
for fear
they should forget them
before the end of the trial.
Silence in court!
Silence in the court.
Herald, read the accusation.
"The Queen of Hearts,
she made some tarts
All on a summer day
"The Knave of Hearts,
he stole some tarts
And took them quite away!"
Consider your verdict.
Oh, no, no, no, no,
Your Majesty. Not yet.
Not yet.
There's a lot more to come.
Really?
Call the first witness!
Oh, I beg your pardon,
Your Majesty,
I was just finishing my tea
when they dragged me in here.
You should have
finished your tea.
When did you begin?
The 14th of March,
I think it was.
15th.
16th!
Don't be impertinent.
Give your evidence
or I'll have you
executed on the spot.
Oh, oh, my dear,
did you hear that?
Bravo!
Oh, Your Honor,
I'm a very poor man,
and I had just begun my tea
not more than
a week or so ago,
and what with the bread
and butter getting thinner
and the twinkling of the tea.
The twinkling of the what?
It began with the tea.
Well, of course,
twinkling begins with a "T."
Everybody knows that.
Do you think I'm a dunce?
Your Honor, I'm a poor man,
and most things
began to twinkle after that.
Only the March Hare said...
I didn't.
You did.
You did!
I didn't.
# Why deny it?
Be a good sport #
# I'll explain it
to all of the court #
# I offered you tea
and you drank a quart #
# I didn't, I didn't
# You did!
# I didn't, I didn't!
# You did! #
He denies it. Strike it out.
Your Majesty,
I'm a poor man.
You're a very poor speaker,
too.
If that's all
you know about the case,
you may stand down.
Stand down, Your Majesty?
But I can
hardly get any lower.
I'm on the floor as it is.
Well, then, simply go!
Of course.
And just
take his head off outside.
Where he goes, I go.
Call the next witness.
Call the next witness!
Give your evidence.
No, I won't.
Your Majesty, you must
cross-examine the witness.
Must I?
Of course you must.
Why must I?
Because I say so.
Oh, of course.
That's different. Yes, yes.
What are tarts made of?
What?
Tarts.
What is a tart made of?
Well, tart starts with a "T."
Then you add an "A,"
then you add an "R,"
then you add...
No! What are the ingredients?
Well, pepper.
Lots of pepper!
They most certainly
are not!
They are made of treacle!
Pepper! Pepper!
Pepper! Pepper! Pepper!
Treacle! Treacle! Treacle!
Treacle! Treacle!
Pepper!
You are an idiot,
it's pepper!
Treacle! Treacle!
Off with his head!
And after that,
pinch off his whiskers.
And off with her head, too!
Treacle. Treacle. Treacle.
Pepper.
Thank you for taking over
the cross-examination,
my dear.
It was giving me
rather a headache.
Well, if these examinations
are really supposed
to be cross,
I am much better
at that sort of thing
than you are.
How true. How true.
Have we a verdict?
You haven't got
any evidence yet.
Silence!
What's the matter?
You're growing, young lady.
But I didn't
eat a piece of mushroom
or drink anything.
There's no doubt about it.
You're growing up.
Can you...
Can you hear me
up there?
Alice,
you're the next witness.
I can hear you.
She's a monster.
The Queen should chop her
down to size right now.
What do you know
about this business?
Nothing.
Nothing whatever?
Nothing whatever.
Oh, that's very important.
How could it
possibly be important?
Unimportant,
Your Majesty means,
of course.
Unimportant,
I meant, of course.
Rule 42.
All persons over a mile high
are to leave the court.
I'm not a mile high.
Yes, you are.
I most certainly am not!
Nearly two miles high.
I don't mean to be rude,
Your Highness,
but you really don't know
what you're talking about.
Besides,
it's not a regular rule.
You invented it just now.
Young lady,
that is the oldest rule
in the book.
Then it ought
to be number one.
Give me a verdict.
Give me a verdict!
But there's more
evidence to come yet.
Please, Your Majesty.
A very important envelope
has just been found.
Why don't you just
let the poor prisoner go?
You can see he's a nice man.
What's in the envelope?
Your Majesty,
a set of verses.
Your Majesty, please.
I didn't write them.
The Knave didn't sign them.
In fact, nobody signed them.
That proves his guilt.
Off with his head.
It doesn't prove anything!
And you really
ought to stop yelling
"Off with everybody's head."
It's a terrible habit
you have.
Silence! Silence!
Just set the prisoner free
and let him go home.
His family probably
misses him very much.
And one of the worst feelings
in the whole world
is to be homesick.
I ought to know.
Give me a verdict.
Give me a verdict!
How can they give a verdict
when there isn't
a bit of meaning
in this whole trial?
Oh, well,
if there's no meaning,
that saves us
a world of trouble.
We don't have to try
and find any.
Sentence first,
verdict after.
Are you crazy?
You can't have
the sentence first.
Hold your tongue.
I will not hold my tongue!
Hold yours!
Ooh! Off with her head!
Off with her head!
Get her. Grab her.
Grab her.
Off with her head!
I'm not afraid of you.
You're nothing
but a pack of cards!
Ouch! Stop it! Stop it!
You wicked little thing!
After her!
Faster!
Faster! Get her! Catch her!
Get her!
Mother, Father, I'm back!
Mother? Father? Anybody?
Dinah, I'm home! I'm home!
What are you doing
on that side of the mirror?
Mother! Father!
I'm here! Look!
I'm here! I'm here!
On the other side
of the mirror!
Mother! Father!
Help me, I'm here!
Mother! Father! I'm here!
On the other side
of the mirror.
"Jabberwocky."
"Twas brillig,
and the slithy toves
"Did gyre and gimble
in the wabe
"All mimsy
were the borogoves
"And the mome raths outgrabe
"Beware the Jabberwock,
my son!
The jaws that bite
"the claws that catch!
"Beware the Jubjub bird,
and shun
The frumious Bandersnatch!"
I can just tell
this is supposed
to be a scary poem.
It's a good thing
I'm grown up
or I probably would be
a little frightened.
Thunder doesn't frighten me.
And I'm not
the least bit afraid.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org