Hi, everyone. I'm Taika Waititi.
Welcome to my commentary
for Thor: Love and Thunder
Um, I'm joined by no one
because they're all too lazy to help.
So, uh... Well, actually, you know what?
That's not true. My daughters are here.
They're somewhere upstairs,
running, uh, amok
here at Abbey Road in London.
Famous Abbey Road, where, um,
the Spin Doctors made all their hits.
Now, I'm also just in this moment...
I just thought... I just thought of
having some glasses of water,
and I thought,
I'll just add some of my own little...
[glasses clinking]
Some little wind chimes
just from some glasses.
You can do this at home if you want.
Just pour water into glasses and just...
[glasses clinking]
And you want to
change the tone, you just... [smacks lips]
- ...drink some of the water.
- [glasses clinking]
Michael Giacchino
did the, uh, score to this film.
[glasses clinking]
- [taps on solid surface]
- [glasses clinking]
I think it would have been better
with some glasses of water.
[chuckles]
I'm tired.
[Waititi] Christian Bale, scabby.
Look at him.
Scabby and sunburnt.
So this girl... Here's a spoiler.
Uh...
She's not actually dead. She's an actor.
That is Chris Hemsworth's daughter.
Christopher Hemsworth,
who plays the titular character
of Thor in this film.
Shocker!
Look at that.
So, um, we thought, you know,
we've promised a big, bombastic,
sparkly, colourful film
full of fun and entertainment.
[voice whispering] You have suffered.
Come to me.
[Waititi] Because the fun
is about to start.
But, you know,
first we want to establish the villain
and what he, uh...
what he's going through.
I love this villain.
Gorr, based on Gorr the God Butcher
from the comic run, uh, God Of Thunder.
God of Thunder. That's right.
Came to me. God of Thunder.
[birds, insects chirping]
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
[groans]
[grunts]
[object stabs]
Ah, what do we have here?
[Gorr grunting]
[Waititi] Uh, this is my friend,
Jonathan Brugh.
Jonny Brugh from New Zealand.
He plays Deacon in the hit movie
I also made, What We Do in the Shadows.
You'll remember him.
He's not this muscly in real life,
and he's not golden.
He, um...
We did all of that to him, uh,
with computers and CGI.
The land is dry.
All life is lost.
[glasses clinking]
[Waititi] A little bit more wind chimes
'cause I think it's appropriate here.
Is this why you celebrate?
[Waititi] Um, fun fact.
That's Christian Bale
from Empire of the Sun.
Empire of the Sun. You remember that?
He's that little kid in that.
No. No, sorry.
There's no eternal reward for you, dog!
What we're celebrating is a fresh kill.
We just vanquished
the holder of the Necrosword...
- [voice] You have suffered.
- ...before he could harm
- any other gods with that cursed blade.
- [voice] if it's revenge you seek.
He threatened to end my entire empire.
But, my lord...
[Waititi] And now, this is the moment
when we figure out that Gorr
has been betrayed by his gods.
Now, what we've created with Gorr
is a sympathetic character,
a sympathetic villain,
in that you don't necessarily
have to agree
with what he's doing
throughout the movie,
but you do understand why he's doing it.
You understand the anger
behind his drive.
And this is where he finds out
that the gods, they laugh at us.
We are mere playthings to the gods.
"As flies to wanton boys," if you will,
if you like Shakespeare.
If you're one of those weird old people
who love Shakespeare.
Oh, no!
Look at that. Being lifted up.
And Jonny Brugh, I can tell you
right now, is also not that tall.
Or maybe he is that tall
and Christian Bale is very short.
Here we go. This is it.
This is when the, uh, black evil sword
named the Necrosword...
Another fun fact. Hela, played by
Cate Blanchett in, uh, Thor: Ragnarok...
If you like the comic books
with God the Gorr Butcher,
then you will recognise
that Hela's sword...
Hela's sword, yes, indeed,
is the Necrosword.
So there's some sort of link
between the two there, isn't there?
Or we decided that the sword
looked cool and just gave it to Hela
'cause we didn't know
if we would make another movie.
Uh-oh. He's killed his first god.
Butchered his first god.
[Rapu] The sword chose you.
[Waititi in mocking voice]
"The sword chose you."
"Oh, no, Gorr cursed!"
[normal voice] Oh, look at that.
He's cursed. Look at those black veins.
You'll notice there that that god, Rapu,
he bleeds gold.
All gods bleed gold.
That's what we establish in this film.
Oh, and all gods will die.
Chop. Thud!
Beheaded. Look at that. Arty shot.
And then we fade out,
and then we got Michael Giacchino
to redo the wonderful Marvel fanfare,
because this film
is a bit rock and roll, man.
It's, uh... We're embracing the wonders
of the electric guitar
and all things '80s rock.
[Waititi vocalises to soundtrack]
L can't believe
We made another Thormovie
Yes, whoa, yes, we did
We, we will never stop
Marvel stud-ios.
Oh, your favourite character, Korg,
introducing the film,
narrating the film.
There he is. Look at him
talking to a bunch of Smurfs in a cave.
Those, uh, creatures are called
the Indigarrians
and were not based on the Smurfs.
But it turns out you can't make anyone
blue without thinking about Smurfs.
That baby... interesting fact
that you probably don't care about...
Uh, that is, um, Brian Chapek's baby.
Brian, um, is one of the producers
on the film.
That shot of him smiling
was from Thor 1 by Kenneth Branagh.
That's his wife. That's Elsa Pataky.
I don't know who the wolf is,
but that's Chris and Elsa
actually making out.
- Ooh, this is wind chime time.
- [glasses clinking]
Romantic.
That's from The Dark World
by Alan Taylor.
I made the job easier on myself
by using other people's footage
from other people's films.
That's from my film.
That's from some Russos film.
That's from Branagh's film.
That's from Alan Taylor's film.
That's from, uh, the Russos' film.
I could name all the shots.
That's from my film!
The best one of all.
[Korg] "What have I done?"
[Waititi] "What have I done?"
This is from the Russos' film.
You remember this one. Endgame.
[Korg] And so he hid his heart
behind a big, fleshy bod
so it could never be broken again.
[Waititi] So this montage, we came up
with this idea for this five years ago.
[Korg] He teamed up
with the Guardians of the Galaxy
and set off on some classic
Thor adventures.
He got in shape.
- Putting in the hard yards.
- [groans]
Turning pains into gains,
and never skipping leg day.
[grunts]
He went from Dad Bod to God Bod.
But beneath his God Bod,
there was still a Sad Bod
just trying to get out.
[shouting]
[Waititi]
Here's the Guardians of the Galaxy.
Chris Pratt.
No notes about Chris Pratt. Just like
saying the words "Chris Pratt."
Get your hands off the glass.
You're putting fingerprints
on the glass.
Just talking to my kids.
Um, there he is. Chris.
God, he's beautiful.
Is that an eyelash on his cheek?
That's annoying.
This here is a little nod to...
whatever kind of witch...
wizardly witch thing
you ever wanted to be acknowledged
in a Thor film.
Some would say Harry Potter. No.
I say Bad jelly the Witch.
It's a story by Spike Milligan.
If you don't know who he is,
then you need to read more books.
Okay. These creatures here are based on
the gang from the original Mad Max film.
And so that main guy, uh, the big white
tuft of hair, that main owl guy,
he's based on Toecutter,
the leader of the gangs in Mad Max.
And George Miller,
greatest filmmaker alive, apart from me,
he came to visit my set and, um,
I got to show him that
and, um, I just...
I wanted him to know that, yeah, he's
a huge influence on me, old Georgie,
and, um, I wanted to pay
a bit of homage to him.
Because we're in Australia,
and what better way to pay homage
to anyone in Australia
than to reference Mad Max?
More Smurfs.
So this guy here, King Yakan...
Yes, it's very nice.
As you know,
we used to live in a peaceful oasis.
- But then our gods were murdered.
- Murdered?
He, um... Stephen Curry.
Stephen Curry. Not Stephen.
That's not Stephen Curry, guys.
Stephen Curry's
the taller one behind him.
Um, no, Stephen is, um, in one
of the best Australian comedies
called... that's right... The Castle.
Um, he's the one who starts
the whole film off by saying,
"My name's Dale Kerrigan,
and this is my story."
Just a little... little nod to that film.
Lots of things
I've ripped off from people
I'm acknowledging at the same time.
They mean the same thing,
"ripping off" and "acknowledging."
It's a sign of, uh, respect.
"Here and now." Okay, cool.
- Uh-oh. Needle drop.
- ["Welcome to the Jungle" playing]
Who is it?
GN R.
Gruns and Snoses.
Sons and Poses.
Runs and Growses.
Runs and Goeses?
They're running and goesing!
On their bikes.
Here comes the first battle of the film.
Go, Chris, go. Go, Chris, go.
And this is not Chris.
That's a stunt double called Bobby.
There's Chris.
[Waititi vocalising
to "Welcome to the Jungle"]
So, uh, Appetite For Destruction
was, uh, one of the first albums
I ever bought when I was a kid.
Loved Guns N' Roses ever since. Um...
No owl... humanoid owls
were destroyed or hurt
in the making of this film, by the way.
Um, and, uh, I have loved Guns N' Roses
ever since.
Decided to put, uh, them in this film,
and I don't even want to know
how much money that cost.
Destruction.
I've got an appetite for it.
Okay, here's a cool part of the film.
One of my favourite parts, actually.
Check this Van Damme...
Look at this Van Damme nod.
["Welcome to the Jungle"
continues playing]
There's Van Damme doing the splits,
but we just stuck Chris's face on him.
And stuck my muscles
on Chris's arms. Yeah!
And jumpy jump.
I know everything that happens
in this movie. I've seen it 500 times.
Whoo, dodge. Triple kick.
Bang, bang.
That's another...
We completely ripped off that from
another Jean-Claude Van Damme move.
He's not going to go into
the temple, is he? No.
Oh.
[Waititi vocalises end of song]
Now, see that background there? That was
all shot on a thing called The Volume.
If you've watched Mandalorian,
which I also directed a little bit of,
um, you'll know that
that's a big LED screen, okay.
It's made of... of hundreds of TVs,
all created...
all, like, stuck together
in a big circular room, 360 degrees,
with a ceiling made of TVs as well.
A lot of TVs.
And, um, that's how
you get those backgrounds.
And that's actually there
when you're shooting,
and actually all the...
the environments that you see on there
also are in the reflections
of the things that you're shooting.
And all the actors get to see
what they're looking at,
to see the environment they're in,
and also it lights the scene as well.
And it's extremely expensive.
Here's Natalie Portman
from the hit movie...
you guessed it... Heat.
I wrote it.
Wait. You're... You're Dr Jane Foster?
I am.
- Hi. [chuckles]
How's the, uh, Einstein-Rosen Bridge?
It's tough.
- Yeah.
- Really tough.
- It's. . . You need a 3D model.
- Oh.
You ever see Event Horizon?
- No.
- [scoffs]
- Interstellar?
- No.
That movie explains everything
really clearly.
Um, all right. The Einstein-Rosen Bridge
folds space,
so that point A and point B...
[Waititi] This reference here
is from, um, Event Horizon.
My very good friend Sam Neill, who's
also in the movie, you'll see him soon.
So he's the first one to do this little
pen through the paper thing.
Then Nolan ripped that off.
Hey, it's filmmakers.
We're all ripping each other off.
Um, so he did that thing, uh...
in, um, Interstellar
And, um, now I've, uh, re-ripped it off
and put it in Thor: Love and Thunder
I hope someone rips this off
and puts it in.
Hopefully, they rip off Kat Dennings's
little noise that she made just there.
That little...
[lips flapping]... noise.
Um, little bit of, uh,
product placement there.
All backwards and unreadable.
In the form of delicious chips.
Or, if you're from
the weirder parts of the world,
crisps.
Stage Four?
Uh-oh. This movie's getting depressing.
Uh, this whole storyline,
with Jane having the old big C,
is from the comic run The Mighty Thor,
which is where this whole thing
with Jane's character, um, comes from,
and I think it's one of the greatest,
uh, comic runs ever, really.
It's an incredible, uh,
use of Jane's character
and she's, um,
challenged with this disease,
but also is able to, you know,
eventually... spoiler...
lift up Thor's hammer
and become a superhero herself.
It's a fantastic story,
and I urge you all to read it.
Um...
[whispers] Ripped it off,
put it in the movie.
[normal voice] So, anyway,
big fan of Natalie.
I've loved watching Natalie
and I've been an admirer of hers
for many years.
And this is our first, uh,
outing together,
treading the old cinematic boards.
So I think we, uh...
I think we hit it off pretty well.
At least that's what she said
in the press junkets.
I wouldn't know.
What does that mean?
Figure it out by yourself.
I'll tell you what it means.
She gets motivated,
she goes into the, uh, lab,
and she starts figuring it out.
That's real blood.
That was, uh, blood
that I took from my, um...
from my big toe.
She's trying to do that thing
where you have that little thumb trick,
but she was doing it wrong just then.
It looks like you've, like,
taken half your thumb and moved it off.
There's nothing in that cup.
Uh-oh, I'm ruining the illusion.
Um, there was probably nothing
on that screen either
when she was looking at it.
So, the Viking myths.
She's called by a sound.
The sound of Mjolnir, the hammer.
Here she comes. She's opening the book.
Then she gets the idea. That's right.
- ["Paradise City" playing]
- Oh, another needle drop!
So if you get Mjolnir, you'll get great
stamina and spirit and great health.
Whoa, could this be a cure?
Maybe it could.
[Waititi vocalises to "Paradise City"]
Now we go to New Asgard.
[continues vocalising]
Look at this
It's turned into a tourist destination
A tourist destination
Now New Asgard
Is a tourist destination
Did you see the alien on the rock there?
Very important that you saw that.
Maybe not obvious enough.
Um...
Look at this. I wonder if we got
any Old Spice money.
We just thought it was funny
that she was advertising Old Spice.
Uh...
I put a lot of work
into that little Old Spice ad.
Infinity Conez is a real thing, guys.
I think it's gonna be at Disneyland.
Infinity Conez.
I came up with that idea.
So this here... look at this...
this is, um,
how... how I imagine things would go
if you were a New Asgardian refugee
on Earth.
You just... You use what you've got,
and what you've got is the resting place
of the famous broken hammer, Mjolnir.
And you've got the incredible
New Asgardian theatre troupe,
the Asgardian Players.
Luke Hemsworth,
that's, um, Chris's brother.
Better looking.
Uh, better actor.
Then you've also got Matt Damon
from the hit movie...
Uh, what was he in? Matt Damon.
The...
Good Will Hunting.
And Sam Neill from Event Horizon. Uh...
And also,
he also played Damien in Omen III.
He played the grown-up Damien,
the devil.
Um, now this here is important.
You think we're just messing around.
Just, like, having fun,
making fun of the last movie,
making fun of the characters
and everything.
We are.
But also, it's important to know
how gods turn into stardust
and also to remember
what happened to Thor's hammer.
That's the whole point of the
theatre show in this film, all right?
And if you don't get that,
then you bloody need to go back
to audience school.
Melissa McCarthy.
[actor Hela]... to stake my claim
as the rightful heir to the throne,
and no one will stop me!
Join me or die!
[Waititi] She's wonderful.
I've had a lovely dinner at her house.
That's not how I convinced her
to do the thing.
All the cameos in this film, basically,
were just, uh, people who happened to be
in Australia at the time
and had nothing to do and were willing
to come and work on this film
for, like, a day for, like, no money.
There's Ben Falcone.
That's Melissa's husband
there on the right, holding her hand.
You can almost feel the power of
these magnificent and immovable stones.
[Waititi] There's Darryl
from the hit little series, uh,
about Thor and Darryl, Thor, uh...
Team Thor, from, uh...
that we shot just before Ragnarok.
If you go on YouTube or one of
those sites and look up Team Thor,
you'll see a whole lot of adventures
with Thor and Darryl
when they're flatmates
together in Australia.
Now, who's this little hobbit?
Who's this one there?
Is that Snow White? Is it Red Riding...
No, it's... [chuckles]
...Jane Foster.
And these are
the broken pieces of Mjolnir.
Mjolnir. The wonderful hammer of Thor.
Now Mjolnir is now coming to life
because Mjolnir and Jane
have a connection.
I don't know if you've seen
the other movies, guys,
but Jane and Thor
used to be boyfriend and girlfriend.
God of Disaster...
[Waititi] I wrote that line,
"God of Disaster." Pretty proud of it.
I think I wrote it.
Look, there's Korg, your favourite.
What is he wearing?
Not him. What's Korg wearing?
You'd think that we just pulled
some of these ideas out of a hat,
but no, these giant goats
are actually from the Norse mythology,
and they've got real classy names
like Toothgnasher and Toothgrinder.
And they are also in the comic books.
So, at this point, who ripped off who?
[goats screaming]
No backsies.
[Waititi] Screechy, screechy goats.
[screaming continues]
Cool little scene here
with the Guardians of the Galaxy
coming up in three, two, one, boom!
Well, my timing was off.
Maybe I haven't seen this film enough.
[Thor] Retrace your steps.
Where did you put the remote?
- One of your goats probably ate it!
- Goats didn't eat the remote.
[Waititi]
Look at that little CGI raccoon!
That's, um, Benjamin...
Um...
What's his name? No, what's his name?
Bradley Cooper.
Benjamin? What the hell?
Um, listen, guys. I don't know people.
I don't know people's names.
I just know their faces.
The goats are gonna be fine.
If not, we can just use them for meat...
[screaming stops]
...ting people.
[Waititi] " ...ting people.
Meeting people."
Another one of my classic lines, guys.
...special whistle that goes
something like this. [whistles]
No, that's not it. [whistles]
No, that's not it.
[Waititi whistles]
"No, that's not it. No, that's not it."
Shall I just do all the lines
with the movie
as opposed to just
telling you guys fun facts
about how nothing was real on the day
and that everything was CGI,
including that wooden thing?
What did we tell you
about jumpin' into new relationships?
That I shouldn't be doing that.
Yeah, you can't get married
on every single planet we land on.
I am Groot.
[Waititi] Uh-oh. Here we go.
Distress calls.
We're about to bring back...
We're about to bring back, everybody,
a classic Thorcharacter.
Character from the Thor mythology
and also the comic books
and also the first two films.
In three, two, one...
two, one...
One, two... One... There she is. Sif.
The wonderful Lady Sif,
as part of the Guardians...
No, what did they call it?
The Warrior... [chuckles]
My friend is in danger.
We must go at once.
[Waititi] The Warriors Three.
The Warriors Three.
Aw, now we get it. We get it.
Thor doesn't want to be alone.
He feels like everyone
leaves him all the time.
Taking a sip of water.
Relax. Chill out. Watch this.
Alas, it's something I'll never have.
- [Waititi smacks lips, exhales]
- [glasses clinking]
After thousands of years of living, you
don't seem to know who the hell you are.
I've been lost before.
But then I found meaning, I found love.
Just taking a moment here to reflect
on this moment between these two guys.
This is kind of like a break-up scene.
Two star-crossed brothers.
Lover brothers.
Not like that,
but, you know, they're in love.
Some people like to use
the word "bromance" quite a lot.
I don't like that word.
I think it's a cop-out.
What if they're just in love?
But it could never be.
Maybe that's a bromance.
[gasps] Oh, my God, he touched him.
You must go. I'll find Sif
You answer the other calis.
The galaxy needs its Guardians.
- Cool, yeah. We were just leaving...
- Shh. I know it hurts.
But it's better this way.
You have to trust me.
To ease the pain, why don't you, uh...
take this ship here
as a parting farewell gift?
Oh, you're giving me my ship?
[Waititi] Is it interesting...
probably not...
that I feel like
when I've got nothing to say,
that maybe means the scene's good?
- I'll start the ship.
- Thank you.
Goodbye, old friend.
Here we go.
Now, I have lots of things to say
because the scene falls apart now.
Because there we go, Taika,
making people do stupid handshakes.
And I don't know if he was acting there
when he said that.
It certainly was not scripted, him
saying, "Certainly dragging this out."
I think he was talking to me.
Hurry up!
Not her.
Remember what I told you.
[Waititi] All right.
Now the movie kicks off.
Check this out.
This is something that Chris and Chris
came up with, this little gag.
I'll still take credit for it, though,
'cause I'm the director.
And off they go. And that's it
for the Guardians, I'm afraid, guys.
So, uh, if you only tuned in
to watch the Guardians,
you are "shoot" out of luck.
And, uh, they're out of here. Uh...
Don't expect them to come back.
They're not gonna come back.
We did originally think maybe there's
gonna be a cavalry scene at the end.
Yeah, like, "They're back in the movie."
But then we thought, "Too predictable.
We don't want to give
the people what they want."
Um, so, nope, they're not coming back.
Too bad.
Anyway, off the real heroes go.
Now they're on a world called Falligar.
Now, the world of Falligar
and this, uh, next, uh, frame here
is directly from the comic book.
Look at this one. We copied it.
What do you think about that?
Guys, I want to introduce you...
introduce you to my d...
my daughters, Matewa...
[Matewa] Hello!
[Waititi] ...and Te Kainga O'Te Hinekahu.
[Te Kainga] Hello.
[Waititi] And, um, so these guys are...
If you listened to the Ragnarok, um,
commentary, Matewa was, uh, on that.
She came in a couple of times.
- You won't even remember that, Matewa.
- [Matewa] No.
[Waititi] No. Anyway, you...
you actually, um, made it way better.
So I'm really happy
that you guys are here. Um...
Now, you've seen the film, kids?
[Matewa] Yeah.
[Waititi] And, uh, what did you think?
[Matewa] Uh, I think it was great.
[Waititi] Yeah? Anything...
Any criticisms?
- [Matewa] What?
- Any criticisms?
Anything you didn't like?
[Matewa] Um, I didn't like
that she was missing an arm.
[Waititi] Yeah, well, you know,
missing an arm is not a cool thing.
[Matewa scoffs]
[Waititi] But she does give
the information about the God Butcher.
[Te Kainga] True.
[Matewa] True.
[Waititi] Asgard is next.
Okay, here's the sleepy little town.
Now, fun fact.
So all the monsters you're about to see
were designed by kids.
Um...
So, when I was writing the script, uh,
TK, Te Hinekahu over here,
my oldest daughter, when she...
I think you must have been
about seven years old.
Um, I was writing, and, uh,
TK looked over my shoulder and she goes,
"What's a... What's a shadow demon?"
I said, "I don't know. I just had to
write down some sort of monster.
But I don't even know
what they look like."
So she went off and she drew
the very first of the shadow monsters,
and it was like a snaky-looking thing.
You'll see it later. It's called Octy.
You'll see it in a scene later on.
And it was a spiky snake-thing with,
like, three eyes and a spiky head
and a nasty mouth.
And that's where the idea came from.
We thought, "You know what we should do?
We should get all of our kids
across the production
to design all the monsters."
That's why these monsters are so freaky,
is 'cause kids did them.
[Te Kainga] Kids don't know
how to draw monsters.
[Waititi laughs]
[Waititi] No, the kids, because...
because kids' designs are more scary,
I think, than what adults can do.
Look at this thing.
[Matewa] But what about
the Demogorgon?
[Waititi] Listen, I'm not here
to talk about Stranger Things.
[Matewa scoffs]
[Waititi] The Demogorgon is scary.
Yes, I'll give you that.
Oh, look at that. See, that's
a spider-snake with a weird crab head.
Look, here comes Valkyrie!
King Valkyrie on... What?
We're not going to say Pegasus.
It's got another name called Warsong.
Warsong. And then here comes Thor.
Right at the s... Right. Perfect timing.
[Te Kainga] With his axe.
[Waititi] And his best friend...
- [person] Look, it's Thor!
- [all cheering]
[Waititi] Korg. Oh, my God. It's me.
- Your father, guys.
- [kids laugh]
[Matewa] I thought his best friend
was his hammer.
[Waititi] Oh, my God. No.
His best friend is me. In real life too.
[Te Kainga] I thought it was his axe.
[Waititi] Um, some kids there
looking out a window.
[grunts]
Loving it.
Look at this big, giant thing.
Some kid drew that. What the hell?
And then we killed it.
So this is a big part.
This is a big, very big,
exciting part of the film.
Ready? Steady?
This is when Thor and Mjolnir,
the hammer, are reunited.
[Waititi, kids making whooshing noises]
- [Waititi] Make the noise for it.
- [all continue making whooshing noises]
[blowing into bottle]
It's me, Thor.
Have you seen my hammer?
Mjolnir, here, boy.
[Waititi] Both times
that we've did the premieres,
Matewa, you were asleep by now.
[Matewa] I know.
[Waititi laughs] Is that because
you found the movie boring?
- [Matewa] Yeah.
- [Waititi laughs]
- [Matewa] Oh, a bit.
- [Te Kainga] Oh, my God.
- [Te Kainga] Dad?
- Yeah?
[Te Kainga] There's also, um...
In the fighting scene...
- [Matewa] And goodbye.
- [Te Kainga] In the fighting scene
with all the other monsters
and the kids...
- [Waititi] Speak into this.
- [Te Kainga] Um...
- There's some...
- [Matewa] The exciting part.
- [Waititi] In the what? Say it again.
- [Te Kainga] In the...
In the scene, um, when...
when the kids are fighting
with the other monsters,
- like, near the end...
- [Waititi] Yeah.
[Te Kainga]... um, I saw
a bigger version of, um, Octy.
- [Waititi] You did? Yeah, we reused him.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
[Waititi] Um...
Okay, so look, so this is something
that Mjolnir was never able to do,
but I thought, "Here's a great idea.
Let's make the hammer even cooler
when it's in, um...
when it's in, uh, Mighty Thor's hands."
[Matewa] Yep.
[Waititi] The competition begins.
Look, he's now changed his look.
[grunting]
Enough tomfoolery.
Why don't you take off that mask
and reveal yourself?
Come on.
[Waititi] And, bingo,
it's his ex-girlfriend, Jane.
Jane?
- [Te Kainga] Boom.
- [Waititi] Boom.
[Matewa] That's the whole thing
about this story,
that Jane and Thor get to meet.
[Waititi] Yes, sir.
[Korg] He was a God of Thunder
and she, a woman of science.
[Waititi] Ooh, this is
that little moment. Look at this.
- This is the history of Thor and Jane.
- [Matewa] Cute.
- [Te Kainga] Eating pancakes.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
[Matewa] Flapjacks.
- [Waititi chuckles] Flapjacks?
- [Matewa] Flapjacks.
[both laugh]
[Waititi] Uh...
- Oh. Fun times with them.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
[Matewa] Yay.
[Waititi] That's my hot dog suit
and that actually belongs
to your Auntie Keisha.
Keisha Castle-Hughes,
from the film Whale Rider
- Um...
- [Te Kainga] Oh!
- [Waititi] Yeah.
- [Matewa] Hot doggy suit.
[Waititi] The hot dog suit.
She left it at my house after a party.
And I've kept it ever since.
And now I've put it in the movie
Thor: Love and Thunder
Now, this is when he charms the hammer
and he tells the hammer
to look after Jane forever.
And that is why... It goes some way
to explaining why she can...
[Matewa] Hold the hammer!
[Waititi] Hold the hammer!
[Te Kainga] But doesn't it kill her?
[Waititi] Oh, come on, man.
- [Matewa] Stop spoiling.
- [Te Kainga] It's just the facts.
[Waititi] Spoiler. What a spoiler.
[Te Kainga] Shush.
[Matewa] But does the hammer
actually kill her?
No, the hammer's not killed...
The hammer's...
Here's the thing about the hammer, okay.
What it's doing is,
she's got cancer and when she's
getting the chemo and stuff like that,
the hammer is purging her body.
It's taking all the impurities
out of her body,
including the chemo.
Which means that the chemo's
having no effect on the cancer.
The cancer's getting worse.
So every time she lifts the hammer,
yes, she is a god,
but when she goes back to being human,
she's even more sick.
Got it?
- [Matewa] Got it.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
This... Oh, God.
We've all been here, haven't we, guys?
Argument like this.
- Right, guys? Right, kids?
- [Matewa] Hmm?
Remember? When I'm like, "Why don't you
guys clean those two damn plates?"
[Matewa] Sure.
- [pop song playing]
- [Korg] Jane wrote a note.
[Waititi] This is, um, a song by ABBA.
- You guys know who ABBA is?
- [Te Kainga] No.
- [Waititi] Yes, you do.
- [Te Kainga] Uh...
[Waititi] Yes, remember?
I played "SOS" quite a lot.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
- [Waititi] It's that band.
And ABBA... I like to think
that ABBA is Thor's favourite band,
'cause they're a tough Viking band
and Thor's a tough Viking.
[Te Kainga] O... Okay. Cool.
It's claustrophobic with the...
the helmet.
[grunts]
[Matewa] He's not claustrophobic.
[Waititi chuckles] But he's acting it.
- [Matewa] 'Cause he loves Jane.
- [Waititi] He does love Jane.
He's freaked out 'cause
he hasn't seen her for so long.
[Te Kainga] Right.
[Waititi] Who do you think... Kids,
who do you think broke up with who?
Do you think Thor broke up with Jane
or Jane broke up with Thor?
[Matewa] Jane broke up with Thor.
[Waititi] Yeah, same.
[Matewa] Thor's just innocent.
- [Waititi] Innocent?
- [Te Kainga scoffs] Innocent?
[Waititi] Yeah, what does that mean?
Dumb?
- [Te Kainga laughs]
- [Matewa] No.
[Waititi] Uh, I think just Thor,
you know, was not mature enough.
He was older than Jane.
He's, like, 1,200 years old, whatever,
1,500 years old.
- [Te Kainga] 1,200.
- [Waititi] And he...
- [Te Kainga] Thinks he is.
- [Waititi exclaims]
[Te Kainga] Geez.
- God.
- [Waititi] Scary.
God, he came out of nowhere! Oh, my God.
God, it's like watching it
for the first time for me.
- [Matewa] Yeah.
- [Te Kainga laughs]
[Waititi] Imagine if this was
my first time
- and I... I didn't even watch the movie.
- [Te Kainga chuckles] Oh, my God.
- [Te Kainga chuckles]
- [Waititi] Whoa.
Hey. Is that the Necrosword?
That's cool.
I've only ever read about it in stories.
Then you know this is going to hurt.
[Waititi] So Christian Bale...
There. That guy there. Christian Bale...
I keep telling this story.
Remember, Matewa, on set?
[Matewa] He was the first Batman.
[Waititi] Well, he wasn't
the very first Batman in history.
- But he was...
- [Te Kainga] Yeah, he wasn't.
[Waititi] You know, some will say, uh...
Not gonna join in the controversy.
But some will say the best Batman.
Um...
Others say Michael Keaton.
Let's not even get into it, okay?
You know, look,
I think even just to play the role
of Batman is an achievement enough.
[Matewa] Let's just talk about
Thor: Love and Thunder now.
[Waititi] Yeah, thank you. God.
Okay. Ooh, look. It's Jane with...
Tough look on her face.
Ooh, there comes Valkyrie.
- [Te Kainga] Even tougher.
- This might be too much for him.
He's gotta get out of here.
But he's got a plan B.
Do you know what the plan B is for Gorr?
[Matewa] To...
To... To... To...
To take all the kids.
- [Waititi] What?
- [Matewa] To take all the kids?
- [Waititi] Correct.
- [Matewa] Yeah. Correct. Yeah.
[Waititi] Sorry, just touching
your microphones.
Don't worry, it's gonna be cree.
But this is part of the real rawness
and the realness of my commentaries.
You know?
Do you think now it's time
for a little bit of a romantic...
[glasses clinking]
- [Te Kainga] No, it's not.
- [Waititi] Wrong time? Okay, cool.
We'll wait. Um...
- [people screaming]
- [creatures growling]
Oh, God, look there's...
How ironic that the... that the monsters
designed by children
are now stealing children.
Have you ever unpacked that?
- Hmm?
- [Te Kainga] They didn't steal me.
[Waititi] No one would steal you.
No one would dare to steal you from me.
[Te Kainga] Hmm.
[Waititi] They'd get a pencil
in the throat.
[kids chuckle]
[Waititi] I'd use them as a... I'd turn...
Whoever tried to do that,
I'd turn them into a pencil case.
- [Matewa] Yeah.
- [Te Kainga chuckles]
[Waititi] And without a zip.
Without a... Without an opening.
- Know what I mean?
- [Matewa] No.
[Waititi] I'd turn them into
a pincushion.
Instead of pins,
there'd be pencils and pens,
- and knives and forks and spoons.
- [kids chuckling]
Eight years they've been...
- They've been separated for eight years.
- [Te Kainga] I thought it was 8 years.
[Waititi] He hasn't really
forgotten about her.
[Te Kainga clears throat]
[Te Kainga beatboxes]
[Waititi] Some beatboxing. I think
it's romantic to have some beatboxing.
Let's do it, kids.
Okay, three, two, one.
- [Waititi, Te Kainga beatboxing]
- [Matewa laughs]
[Matewa] Oh, my God.
Nope, nope, nope. No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
[Waititi rapping] Romance
It's romance between Thorand Thor
It's Jane and Thorand Thor
And Mighty Thor
And the original Thor
Here we go now into the next scene
The next scene is in the town hall
- [Matewa whoops]
- [Waititi] Okay, you guys are...
Auntie Shar...
Don't... Watch out for that mike.
Auntie Shari is gonna be here soon.
Watch this.
- Oh, no, in a second.
- [Te Kainga mock laughs]
[Matewa] You... Oh, no, in a second.
- [Waititi] Oh, there's Matt Damon.
- [Te Kainga] Hello.
- [Waititi] And Luke Hemsworth.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
[Waititi] Do you know who Matt Damon is?
[Te Kainga] Uh...
[Waititi] We'll delete that.
[Matewa] He looks like Loki.
- [Te Kainga] Mm-hmm.
- [Waititi] Mmm...
Don't tell him that.
Okay. So, check this out.
The one that got away.
[Thor] The one that got away.
[Matewa] "The one that got away."
[Waititi] "The one that got away."
"The one that got away." Is it?
Does it sound like Korg?
"The one that got away."
[Matewa chuckles]
[Te Kainga] He's trying to get it back.
[Waititi] He's trying to get
the hammer back.
Now we've created
this lovely moment in this film,
which I think is fantastic,
which is, um,
the little jealousy triangle between...
Stormbreaker...
between Stormbreaker
and Mjolnir and Thor.
- [Te Kainga sighs]
- Stormbreaker's jealous of the old...
Don't sigh like that.
It's not that boring.
Here we go. Do you see that?
Look, there's Shari.
- Do you see her?
- [kids] No.
- [Waititi] Aw, we just missed her.
- [Te Kainga groans]
[Waititi] She was the one yelling.
That's your auntie.
[Te Kainga] Oh, yeah. Then I saw that.
- [Waititi] Uh-oh.
- [Matewa] Starting a fight.
[Waititi] Would you believe
all of this was shot in Australia?
[Te Kainga] No.
- [Waititi] I know.
- [Te Kainga chuckles]
I see what's happening here.
You're afraid.
[Waititi] I would maybe believe it
because all the kids have got
Australian accents.
[Te Kainga] True.
Afraid.
Anxious.
[marker squeaking]
If we are to find the children,
we must first look within ourselves.
I'm sorry. Miek, it's very hard
to give a rousing speech with the...
[Waititi] Okay, guys. Okay, guys. Okay.
See the whiteboard there?
See that? Okay.
I want to tell you guys something.
The entire movie is all laid out
in the pictures on that whiteboard.
Everything that happens in the movie
is on that whiteboard.
And that's the information
I wanted to give you.
Um, I've never told anyone that.
So now you can go and pause it
and you can have fun looking through
every single little bit of that,
and it shows you what happened.
It may even have...
And I'm telling you this from my heart...
It may even have some deleted scenes
on that whiteboard too.
- [Te Kainga exhales sharply]
- [Waititi] Yep, I know. I know.
Crazy.
He aiso wields the Necrosword.
How do I know that?
[child exhales into mike]
[Waititi] Stop purring into the mike.
- [blows on mike]
- [Waititi] Don't.
Just sit back, and if you want
to say something, you lean forward.
...but it slowly corrupts and kills
whoever wields it, which means...
[Waititi clinking glasses]
[Te Kainga] Wrong time again.
We're up against a cursed,
shadow-zombie kidnapper.
Awesome. When do we leave?
[Astrid] Thor.
Can you see me?
Uh, floating head alert.
It's Astrid. Heimdall's son.
Astrid, are you okay?
I no longer go by the name Astrid.
I'm now known as Axl.
[Waititi] Look at him.
He's more than just a head, though.
- You're about to meet the rest of him.
- [Te Kainga] Mm-hmm.
I intend to honourhis wishes.
- Axl.
- Astrid.
- I said Axl.
- Axl!
- It's asshole. Now listen to him!
[Waititi] Oh. What?
- [Matewa] That was you.
- [Waititi] That was the character.
Your father taught me
and I'm gonna teach you.
[Waititi] So if you remember the movie
you loved so much, Ragnarok,
you'll remember the magic eye is
where Thor got to go back to Asgard
and visit, um, Heimdall
using ghost powers... vision ghost.
Hey, how's it going, kids?
"How's it going?" Look where we are.
We're in a cage made of spikes.
Yes, right. Not good. Yeah.
Are you gonna do something?
Yes. Yes, I am, but just not right now.
I'm the vision ghost. Look.
[Waititi] Um, another fun fact.
Commentaries should just be called
Series of Fun Facts.
Another fun fact.
Um, Natalie Portman's kids are in here,
in this scene.
So, if you die,
you'll end up in Valhalla.
- Oh, my God. Go away.
- Wait, wait. Listen.
- [rumbling]
- [children scream]
Okay. It's all right, children.
Don't cry. Don't cry. It's okay.
[Waititi] And also,
another boy called Rex,
who's, uh, Christian Bale's child,
was also down in the corner.
Down there in the yellow cape. It's Rex!
- [Matewa] He has another child?
- [Waititi] Christian?
- Yeah.
- [Waititi] He's got a bunch.
- [Matewa] Oh.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
Look, they're on a... a rock boat,
hurtling towards
the black and white part of space,
"the place where colour fears to tread."
I'm gonna get you out of here.
- I'm scared. We all are.
- [children crying, whimpering]
[children] Thor! Thor! Save us.
[Waititi] Now, this is really
just a moment
to show that Thor is not equipped
to deal with kids.
He's just used to
looking after himself, being alone.
Kids freak Thor out.
But, hey, we know what happens later on.
- [Matewa] Yeah.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
Let's bring the rainbow.
"Bring the rainbow"?
Is that a catchphrase or something?
She's only been a Thor for a minute.
I mean, saving lives, she's quite good
at. But the rest of it, she needs work.
- How many catchphrases have there been?
- A lot.
Yep. Jumped the gun.
Hang on, he moves through shadows
and he's going to the Shadow Realm.
It seems like that's where
he's going to be the most powerful.
You're right. We can't just go
marching in there. It could be a trap.
[Waititi] Any questions, you guys?
- [Te Kainga] No.
- [Waititi] Okay. Um...
- Thinking what?
- I'm thinking it too.
- Omnipotence City.
- [Korg] Mmm.
What's Omnipotence City?
[Waititi] What about now?
We could pull together
the greatest team ever.
We could recruit Ra, Hercules,
Tumatauenga.
Quetzalcoatl, maybe. And Zeus,
the oldest and wisest of them all.
[Matewa] Is there only two swear words
in this movie?
[Waititi] Like what?
[Matewa] 'Cause when the girl
who, um, lost an arm said, um...
'Cause when the girl
who lost an arm said the S-H-word,
and then when you said the A-word.
[Waititi] Yeah. Uh, those are
the only two I can think of.
[Matewa] Okay.
Cool.
Stormbreaker just needs a conduit.
Anything that can handle space travel.
I love it when she talks shop.
It has the power to get us there,
it just needs something to focus that
energy so it's not so unpredictable.
You know, uh, if we had a ship
we could harness it
and use Stormbreaker as a power source.
- Oh, like an engine.
- Like an engine.
You need a ship?
I've got a ship.
[goats scream]
Get rid of all those seats.
And you guys,
go tie those goats to the front.
We leave in 15 minutes.
Essentiais only, everyone.
That's essential. Mm-hmm.
[person] Fifteen minutes to departure!
Well, you moved on quick,
didn't you? [chuckles]
You're some piece of work.
[Waititi] More jealousy.
- Just catching up with an old friend.
- Yeah.
I've been meaning to apologise.
Sorta acting a little weird before. I
just haven't really been myself lately.
You know, kind of ..
[Waititi] We built this entire town
in Australia, um, out in the suburbs.
We built
an entire Norwegian fishing village.
I mean...
I mean, why?
I know why.
'Cause it's a movie, and we needed it.
But, God, it's a big effort, isn't it?
All of the cobblestones and everything
were all hand... hand-cobbled.
What do you say?
Hand-pounded into the ground?
We put a lot of effort in, guys.
It's as much effort
as Chris put into those arms.
[Jane] See you later.
[person] Five minutes to departure!
[Matewa] Oh, no.
What?
We were just talking.
[Waititi] Now we get a bit of backstory
with Jane. Okay, like, what drives her.
And, uh...
this is where we understand,
oh, Jane is still sick.
Don't be afraid.
Even when I'm gone, honey...
[Waititi] Her mother told her
when she was a kid,
"Keep on fighting, no matter what."
So she's kind of doing this
for her mother,
- and also, because her mother told her...
- [Matewa] "Elaine Foster."
[Waititi] Elaine Foster.
[Elaine] Never stop fighting.
[Waititi] So she's like,
"No, I'm gonna keep going.
No matter what."
[Matewa] Is that a bed on the ship?
[Waititi] No, this is
a little apartment on, uh... on Earth.
My good friend,
Ondine Seabrook, um, from Sydney,
uh, painted that painting there
behind, uh, Tessa.
I've always loved that painting.
You're a Viking now.
Means you pretty much
have to die in battle...
[Waititi] Do you guys
like that painting?
[Matewa] Sure.
I haven't seen it up close.
[Waititi] Yeah, it's beautiful up close.
- [Matewa] But it looks cool from afar.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
I love my people,
but it's all meetings and raven-mail
and meetings
that could've been raven-mail.
I miss fighting.
I miss my sisters.
Which is why you need to come,
'cause I need one.
[Waititi] There's a fun... [coughs]
There's a fun bit.
Do you guys know what this song is
coming up?
A hand grenade?
No. It's a portable speaker.
["Family Affair" plays]
[Waititi vocalising to "Family Affair"]
Mary J. Blige.
Okay, here we go, guys.
We're off on our adventure.
Now, this joke coming up
is something I'm very proud
to have put into the film.
Some people with...
We will return with children.
[Waititi] Closed-minded people didn't
like this joke, but I love this joke.
And then we shall feast!
- Not on the children.
- [crowd murmuring]
We do not do that anymore.
Those were dark times. Shameful times.
[Waititi] They used to eat kids, guys.
They used to eat kids.
Okay, here they go.
- [Matewa] Humans used to eat kids?
- [Waititi] Vikings did.
Listen, do you know
what the Vikings used to do?
- [Matewa] What?
- [Waititi] Real bad stuff.
- [Matewa] Like what?
- [Waititi] I don't even want to say.
It's not even for kids' ears.
So, you know,
let's acknowledge the kind of, uh...
Let's acknowledge, you know, just what
it meant to be a Viking back in the day.
And to be a Space Viking? Ooh.
- I mean, I shudder to think.
- [Matewa] That wasn't mean.
[Waititi] Oh, yeah, look at this.
We're in Omnipotence City.
Now, Omnipotence City is
something from the comic books.
A lot of the things
in all of the Marvel movies,
if you know, you know.
Um, if you know your stuff,
they all come from the comics.
[Matewa] What did Vikings do to people?
[Waititi] What did Vikings do to people?
- Yeah, like kids.
- [Waititi] They used to, like...
I mean...
they used to ride around on boats,
invading other people's
towns and villages and stuff
- and they used to capture people...
- [Te Kainga] What did they do to kids?
[Waititi] They used to, probably, like,
make kids work.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
- They used to make kids, like...
make kids, like, work all day long.
- [Te Kainga] Mm-hmm. And?
- [Waititi] And, um...
Oh, that's such a good one.
[Waititi] They might, like,
take away all of their toys.
[Matewa] That's not mean.
That's not mean.
[Waititi] Yes, it is.
I don't want people taking my toys away.
Uh-oh. She's like, "Have you
got a girlfriend?" Uh-oh. What?
Just the work and everything.
Cool. Gonna check this place out.
[Waititi] You guys hungry?
[sighs, chuckles]
[Matewa] Mmm. No, I'm good.
The buildings are cool.
[Waititi] You know who's cool?
Tessa Thompson.
[Te Kainga] Yeah.
Feelings? What, for Jane?
No, don't be ridiculous. Feelings.
[Waititi] And you know what?
Tessa and Chris together on screen
is a fantastic duo.
They're so...
They're always so good together.
- [Te Kainga] Who?
- [Waititi] These two.
[Te Kainga] Oh.
Yeah.
[Waititi] She's got the best laugh.
Look at him.
He's like,
"Oh, I don't know what to do."
He's falling back in love with Natalie.
Okay, here comes
Te Hinekahu's, um, Octy.
The very first, uh, monster
that was designed for this film.
About to show its face.
- [Te Kainga] I have a toy called Octy.
- [Waititi] Yeah, I know. You do.
And guess what kind of animal is that?
- [Te Kainga] An octopus.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
An octopus. Yeah.
With all this talk
about chopping off heads,
I wanna have a go.
What's this?
Oh.
[Waititi] "Oh."
Uh, screen saver.
This is Octy. Hello, Octy.
[Waititi] There we go. Look! Octy.
There he is. So there's the spiky snake.
Sorry, TK, but your beloved...
[Te Kainga gasps] My creation!
[Waititi] Your creation
- just got beheaded.
- No!
[Te Kainga] Oh, come on.
All right, all right, all right.
Octy's gone.
[screaming]
Come on. [shushes]
I'm scared.
Oh, look at you.
I knew a little girl just like you.
And she was brave, and she was smart...
[Waititi] And she was
Chris Hemsworth's daughter.
[Matewa] Called Indi.
[Waititi] Called Indi. India.
India Hemsworth.
...about gods.
They're meant to protect you, right?
Well, where are they?
[Waititi] There's some good acting
by that girl.
Look at that werewolf kid behind him.
That lycan kid.
- Look at him!
- [Te Kainga] I know.
[Waititi] I just...
just thought it would be a cool idea
to put a werewolf kid in there.
[Matewa] It's cool. It's cool.
[Waititi] Okay, so now we're in
the t-t-t... golden temple of the gods.
And...
this is where we see all of the gods
of the universe all gathered.
And this is where... where Thor is trying
to gather an army of gods
to go and fight the God Butcher.
Holy shit.
[Matewa] And this is
where we see a Maori person.
[Waititi] This is where
we see a Maori god.
A Maori wahine.
Atua.
- Um...
- [Matewa] What god is that?
[Waititi] There's... Atua is...
I didn't want a name to her because...
Okay, let's look quickly at these gods.
Okay.
[Matewa] Ooh, snake.
[Waititi] Good magic.
Look at the eyeball!
I feel like that's the god of voyeurism.
She said "god of carpentry,"
which I was...
'cause I suggested it was Jesus.
- [Matewa] What's that god?
- Look at Bao. I came up with that idea.
I've got so many good ideas.
I came up with the...
the idea for a god that's a dumpling.
There's Ninny of the Nonny.
Did you notice that his throne
is made of scissors?
- [Te Kainga] Yes.
- Those are all scissors he's conquered,
because in the game
of Rock Paper Scissors,
rocks destroy scissors,
and those are the ones that he's beaten.
And that's the end of that story.
[Te Kainga] I wonder if
paper's beaten him.
[Waititi] Do you think that
the god of scissors
has got a throne made of paper?
[Te Kainga] Mmm.
[Matewa] The god of Ninny Nonny,
is he, um... is he your god?
- [Waititi] Yeah.
- [Matewa] Oh!
- Cool.
- [Waititi] Yeah. Yeah.
[Te Kainga] Wow.
[Matewa] Well, then
I like that god the most.
[Waititi] Aw, cool.
- [Te Kainga] Zeus!
- [Waititi] I also love this god.
[Matewa] Zeus!
- [Waititi] Look, you know who it is?
- [Te Kainga] Yes, it's Russell.
[Waititi] It's Russell.
We went and stayed
on Russell's farm, didn't we?
[Te Kainga] Yeah.
[Waititi] We played with his dogs
and we went on his... the quad bikes.
- And he's got an awesome pool.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah.
[Waititi] And a games room.
That was cool.
[Matewa] Because that pool,
you could jump off the waterfall.
[Waititi] What's that?
[Matewa] 'Cause that pool,
you could jump off the waterfall.
[Waititi] Yes, that's right.
But we're not here
to talk about Russell's cool farm.
We're here to talk about
Thor: Love and Thunder
So this is...
So Zeus and Hercules and all of those,
you know, those Greek gods,
they are actually characters again.
And not only in real... real mythology,
but, um, also in the Marvel universe.
Marvel comic universe.
And, uh,
it was really cool to be able
to introduce Zeus to everyone
in the form of Russell Crowe,
who is one of my favourite actors
of all time.
And, um, also, I now like to
count him as a friend of mine.
That was the, uh, Maori god there,
when she's clapping, um,
with her, uh, ponum... pat...
- And...
- [Te Kainga] Her feather in her head.
[Waititi] The feather in her head.
[playing gentle music]
I hereby open...
this holy council of the god.
[Waititi] So, fun fact. Um...
So, Russell did, um, all of the takes
in a Greek accent
and also in a British accent,
because we weren't sure which one
would be better, which would be funnier.
You know,
maybe one needed to be more serious.
And in the end, um, everyone loved
the, uh, Greek accent more.
Um, including me.
I thought it was fantastic.
- [Te Kainga] Same.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
- [Matewa] Papa?
- Yeah?
[Matewa] Do you really
have to be, um, in a disguise?
Because you're one of the, um...
You're a rock person.
And then the Ninny god...
Ninny Nonny god is there, so...
- [Waititi] Right.
- [Matewa] Do you really have to?
[Waititi] Well, um, you know...
Logic police over here. No, maybe not.
- These guys.
- Korg, shut up.
But I'm joining in with those guys.
'Cause, like, you know,
maybe I didn't need to,
but it's good
'cause I'm part of their team.
- [Matewa] Oh.
- I'm part of their team,
so I should just jump in a disguise too.
Whew.
Hello.
[Waititi] Okay, here comes...
Here comes a moment that, um... [chuckles]
[Matewa] It is in... inappropriate?
[Waititi] It's, uh... Oh, I think it's
highly appropriate. I think it's fine.
- [Te Kainga] It's just funny.
- [Waititi] It's just a butt. But, uh...
[Te Kainga] You're spoiling.
[Waititi] Well, yeah.
I think everyone's seen the trailer.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah, true.
- The only thing everyone talks about.
[Thor] Coming through. [grunts]
Oops. Sorry.
[Korg] Good luck, bro.
[Matewa] Was that a god too?
[Waititi] Yeah, they're all gods.
[Matewa] Okay,
then he stepped over a god.
MightyZeus!
[chuckles] Wow!
Gods of the universe,
I come here to ask foryourhelp,
to raise an army.
There's a maniac called the God Butcher
who seeks to end us all.
His destruction is everywhere.
Entire planets, realms...
have been left completely unprotected.
He's left nothing but chaos in his wake.
But I know where he is,
and with yourhelp we can crush him
before he kills anyone else.
[Zeus] That guy...
[Waititi imitating Zeus] "That guy."
Boo-hoo.
If that's all,
pretty boy,
you go back to your seat
and you be quiet.
Yeah, I'm sorry. Did you not
hear any of what I just said?
He's... He's murdering en masse.
[Waititi] Also Russell's real hair here.
Here, his real hair.
His real hair.
- [Matewa] His real hair?
- [Waititi] And his real beard.
You cannot come to the orgy!
- You have to listen to us!
- [Zeus] That's it!
Shackle!
- [Waititi] Uh-oh.
- [Te Kainga] Uh-oh.
[Matewa] Here it comes.
- What is the signal? Mmm.
- It'll be, "Go. "
[Zeus] Let's see who you are.
I take off your disguise.
And fiick!
[Matewa] Oh, God.
[crowd gasps]
[Waititi] Uh-oh.
[crowd exclaims]
You fiicked too hard, damn it!
[Waititi] There was a tattoo there.
"Rip Loki." "RIP Loki."
Um...
I originally wanted an "RIP Loki" tattoo
in, uh, Ragnarok,
but I'm glad we waited to make it, uh,
such a feature in this one.
There you go.
Now those disguises are gone.
You are Thor,
the God of Thunder.
But is not thunder
just the sound of lightning?
[Waititi] Whoa.
Flex-a-flex-a-rooni, old Chris there.
Zeus, this is bigger than us.
He's taken Asgardian children.
Who do you think we are? The god police?
Every god watches over
their own peoples.
Nothing more, nothing less.
Asgardian problems...
[Waititi] "Are Asgardian problems."
Now this is where we get to the crux,
right, guys?
So we're realising the gods actually
may be not worth saving
because they really are self-centred
and they only care about themselves.
And, um, maybe Thor is one of the very
few gods who actually does care.
Anyway, that was that rant.
So...
Russell in a close-up. Nothing better.
Gorr has the Necrosword...
which means he could kill us.
Notgood. Two...
I know you're trying
to do the right thing.
[Waititi] How you guys doing
with this bit? Enjoying it?
[Te Kainga] Mm-hmm.
[Waititi] Is this the first time
you've seen this bit, Matewa?
[Matewa] Yeah, I've seen it.
Well, I might've fell asleep
on this part,
but I've seen it in...
when you were actually making it.
[Waititi] Yes, that's right.
You were there, remember?
And I told you off
and I put you in the corner.
- [Matewa] Wait, what?
- [Waititi] Yeah.
You were making too much noise
and being... misbehaving.
- I've got a photo of it.
- [Matewa chuckles]
[Waititi] Oh, here we go.
We need your lightning bolt.
My lightning bolt is called Thunderbolt.
So, I think to use
somebody's secret weapon like this...
[Waititi clinking glasses]
[Matewa] Can I try?
[crowd cheering]
[crowd gasps]
[crowd exclaims]
No!
[crowd laughs]
Do not worry.
The God Butcher,
he will not reach Eternity.
Eternity?
[Waititi] So now we're coming up
to a nice big fight,
which, um, has got a bit
of influence, um, behind it
from the great Kurosawa.
And this is, uh, in terms
of the, uh, blood sprays,
which you can obviously... you'll see
in a lot of, uh, martial arts films,
and, uh... including Kill Bill
Um...
Oh, important bit of information there,
that she just said.
Eternity is a...
basically a wishing well.
It's a... It's a being.
If you reach it you can...
If you're the first to reach it,
you can wish for whatever you want,
and that's what Gorr is trying to do.
Gorr the God Butcher
wants to get to Eternity
so he can wish for the death of all gods
and effectively end everything.
I am afraid I cannot allow that.
This is a secret place
known only to the gods.
You know where we are.
The God Butcher
could use you to find us.
This is no good.
So now...
[Waititi] "You have to stay."
Oh, "You must stay."
Oh, here we go. Fighty-fight time.
Yes. Rush his bum.
Hell, yeah!
[crowd gasps]
[Waititi] Probably the most important
part of this fight, um...
as you guys are probably well aware,
is the demise of one of the most
beloved characters in the MCU,
Korg the Rock Man.
Look at this wonderful fighting.
I did a bit of this stuff, guys.
A lot of people think
I didn't do any of this
and I was just the voice,
but I was there most of the time, um,
in my little mocap suit,
doing the actual actions
and doing little stunty fight bits.
And, yeah,
I just want you guys to know, yeah,
I'm just as committed
as the other actors.
Just can't see my beautiful face.
Too distracting.
Uh-oh.
Goodbye, Korg. Three, two, one. Splat.
[Matewa] No!
[Waititi] Guys, your father is about to
die on-screen. What do you think?
[Matewa] What?
[Te Kainga] I would hate that and cry.
[Matewa] You... "I'm perishing."
Zeus!
You're next, Odinson!
[Waititi] "I'm perishing!"
Uh-oh. Boo!
One Australian
killing another Australian.
Russell Crowe, though, um,
can we just all acknowledge, by the way,
originally is from New Zealand.
- [Matewa] Did he actually...
- He's a New Zealander.
- [Matewa] Did he actu...
- Russell Crowe is a New Zealander.
- [Te Kainga] We know.
- Russell Crowe.
- [Te Kainga] We know. We know.
- Russell Crowe's a New Zealander.
- [Matewa] Did he actually fall?
- Russell's a New Zealander.
- [Matewa] Did he actually...
- He's a Kiwi. He's like me.
- [Matewa] Did he actually fall, though?
- He didn't fall, no.
He would be...
actually be dead if he fell.
- I need you to call the goats.
- I'll do my best.
[Waititi] Oh, hello!
Korg's still alive, by the way.
[grunts]
Now you've got my six.
[Waititi] You want some water?
Want some water?
I can do this, damn it. [whistles]
No, that's not it. No, that's not it.
[whistles] Nope.
Come on, Korg, purse those lips.
[breathes deeply]
[Waititi imitates whistle]
And the third Guns N' Roses needle drop
in three, two, one, and...
- [vocalises] Bam. Boom.
- [Te Kainga] Bam.
["Sweet Child O' Mine" playing]
[Waititi, Te Kainga vocalising
to "Sweet Child O' Mine"]
[Waititi] "Sweet Child O' Mine."
Damn! What a banger this song is!
- Never gets old.
- [Matewa] I like this song.
[Waititi] This song is insane, man.
Can you imagine those guys?
They were probably... How old were they?
Kids, how old was Guns N' Roses when
they, um... when they made this song?
About 22, 20?
- [Te Kainga] Maybe.
- [Waititi] Yeah, maybe.
Man, what did I do when I was 20?
Nothing.
I was a late bloomer.
That's the other thing that I'd like
to impart to you two, my darlings.
There's no hurry, all right?
Yeah, sure, you can put out
"Sweet Child O' Mine"
when you're 20 or 21, but then...
you know, then what?
- Then it's just...
- [Matewa] Wait, what?
[Waititi] Then it's just Lies,
and then Use Your Illusion land ll.
I'm saying, like, you know,
I didn't start making films
till I was 30,
and I'm cool with that, you know.
So, like, 30 years of just waiting
around and trying to figure it out.
No hurry, okay?
I just don't want you guys to rush
into something thinking like,
"Oh, you know, I've got to, you know...
I've got to have it all sorted out
by the time I'm 20."
You don't have to have it
all sorted out.
You can still be finding yourself.
[Matewa] I want to be in a movie
when I'm just a kid,
like a kid director.
[Waititi] Like a kid actor or kid
director? You want to be a kid director?
[Matewa] Kid director and a kid actor.
- [Waititi] Like me, but a kid?
- [Matewa] Yeah.
[Waititi] Damn.
- Just like...
- [Matewa] Like...
[Waititi] And would you direct
a movie full of kids?
[Matewa] Huh?
[Waititi] Would you
direct a movie full of kids?
There's lots of other kids in the movie?
[Matewa] Sure. And it will be
a scary movie like Stranger Things.
[Waititi] Like a scary...
Like a scary Bugsy Malone.
- [Matewa] Yep.
- [Waititi] Mmm.
What about you?
[Te Kainga] What are we talking about?
[Waititi] What do you want to do
later on in life?
- [Te Kainga] I don't know.
- [Waititi] Yeah. Good answer.
You don't need to know. You're young.
Just enjoy the here and now.
I... Personally...
And I'm saying this on a DVD commentary
which is gonna last forever.
I don't even know
if you should go to university.
And there you go.
There's the silence I wanted to hear.
Did it do anything for me? I'm not sure.
- [Te Kainga] Okay.
- [Matewa] Yeah.
[Waititi] Okay.
Very important part of the movie
coming up here, a very romantic part.
I don't know if I'm gonna
say anything during this little scene.
- Because what is there to say?
- [Matewa] Then don't say anything.
[Waititi] I'm just
leading up to that. Um...
He's making peace with his ex.
Great. We love that.
Um...
Listen, uh,
are we good?
Yeah?
[Waititi] I said "um" as if, like, I had
something important to say, but I don't.
Can I also thank you guys
for helping me out on this?
'Cause I find these commentary things
quite difficult.
I always start with a lot of energy
and I've got great stories.
[Matewa] What are you drawing?
- [Waititi] When? What?
- [Matewa] What are you drawing?
- [Waititi] Where, here?
- Yeah.
[Waititi] On this pad?
I don't know. Some squiggles.
Cool doodles.
- [Matewa] Doodling.
- Doodling. Let's start a new page.
[Te Kainga] Can I do some doodling?
- [Matewa] Can I do some doodling?
- [Waititi] Sure.
Here, I'm gonna give you
some page... papers.
It's quite the view, huh? [chuckles]
Yeah. Beautiful.
- [Waititi groans]
- [paper tears]
Oops. I just ruined the pad.
There you go.
- [Matewa] Wow.
- [Te Kainga] Oh, my God.
- [Waititi] There you go. You got a pen?
- [Te Kainga] You really broke that.
[Waititi] Ah, here we go.
You can just delete that little bit
about paper out, if you want.
But, um, that's real life, isn't it?
So you'll be deleting life. So, killer.
Now, look at these space dolphins.
[Thor] So beautiful. So rare.
Very loyal creatures.
They mate for life, in packs of six.
Just love.
[Korg singing] With a hey-ninny-nonny
And a fair-finny-fonny
Oh, brother
Man, you look so hot
L wanna get in your rocks
When we get together
We're gonna get it on
And we're gonna make some babies
[Waititi] Listen, I'm very proud
of the representation in this film.
The LGBTQIA+.
...and they go down to a little lava pool,
and they hold hands over the hot lava...
and then, after a month,
they pull their hands apart...
and they find they've created
a beautiful new Kronan baby boy.
[Waititi] I, uh... It's...
But the storyline behind Korg
and the Kronans, um, being a race of...
a species of ma...
of men, male rock people.
Um, I don't even know if you'd say men.
But, uh, that they're... that they, um,
all make babies together.
The men make babies together.
Uh, so they go into a volcano
and they hold hands.
This is a whole story that comes from
the comics, okay? So that's canon. Um...
And that was something
that I thought was so awesome.
And I thought, "Well, then we've got
to acknowledge that in the film."
We've got to show that, like,
it's just normal.
And so I think, with a lot of
the representation in the film,
I feel very proud that, you know,
we're going some way at least.
I know it's, you know...
it's a big film and, you know,
only small little parts
of the film deal with it,
but I think it's, you know,
at least great to normalise it.
And that we don't have some big soapbox,
stupid, big monologue.
That we don't have some big monologue
where someone's, like, saying,
"It's okay to be different," um,
in front of 400 people.
You know, those big speeches
that you often have to have in films.
I like that it's just something
that no one really even discusses.
It's just accepted, and people are gay.
And that's cool.
Um, I do like the idea that, you know,
that young people who are, um...
who are questioning...
questioning themselves,
who are trying to figure it out,
can watch a film like this and go,
"Oh, hey, I'm not alone."
It's actually normal in this world
of comic book superheroes.
- Wait. What's happening?
- Bye.
[Waititi] Okay, intense moment here.
What did I say? I didn't mean that.
Just kidding.
I don't have cancer.
Let's go smash something.
Jane, I'm so sorry.
Don't be sorry for me.
When did you find out?
Um, like six months ago. I...
I was just feeling tired,
and then they told me I have Stage Four.
Get my affairs in order.
And then I heard Mjolnir calling me
so I thought maybe,
if science isn't working
maybe Viking space magic.
[Waititi] It's not that I don't have
anything to say right now, everyone.
It's just that, uh, I don't need
to say anything.
I've talked quite a lot.
Let's just sit
and just watch this moment, then I'll...
I'll start piping up again in a minute.
Jane, none of us know how long we have.
We don't know what tomorrow holds.
And Mjolnir...
Mjolnir chose you.
And it chose you because you're worthy.
And that's something.
When I first met you,
I was unworthy.
I was unable to pick up that hammer.
But you taught me
there is no greater purpose
than to help those in need.
You made me worthy.
So whatever you wanna do,
we can do together.
Okay.
Now what do you wanna do?
I wanna get those children
back to their families.
I wanna finish that mission.
Spoken like a true Thor.
How do you feel now?
So scared.
How are you feeling?
Shitty.
How shitty?
- Really shitty.
- Well, then...
[Matewa] Ugh.
[Waititi laughing]
Oh, that was the response
I was hoping for.
Oh, my gosh. That was great.
[Matewa] Ew. That was "ew."
[Waititi] That was not "ew."
Kissing's good.
[Matewa] Kissing's... ew.
[Waititi] Ew? What do you mean "ew"?
What's wrong with kissing?
- [Matewa] It's disgusting.
- [Waititi] Not disgusting.
What do you think about kissing?
- [Te Kainga] It's okay.
- [Matewa] I don't like it.
[Waititi] Okay, look, guys. Here we go.
Look at this moon. The moon, the moon.
The moon of shame.
All the colour's draining out of them.
It's turning into a Truffaut film.
Guys, can I just take this opportunity
just to tell everyone
to please turn off
the motion-blurring thing on your TVs?
Can I just remind everyone,
if you're watching this on your TV,
which you probably are,
go into settings, turn off
any of that frame-blending thing,
that motion blur thing,
anything that makes everything
look like a cheap soap opera.
Um, okay?
These... These TVs are too advanced now,
and they're ruining pictures.
[wind howling]
Where are they?
[Waititi] You need to have
a character ask where the kids are,
so that you are reminded
that they're looking for the kids.
[gasps] Romance.
[Matewa] What do you mean?
[Waititi] What do you mean,
what do I mean?
- [Waititi clinking glasses]
- [Matewa] What do you mean, "romance"?
[Waititi] Romance.
They were holding hands.
This is perfect timing for the...
[clinking continues]
Ooh, listen. Guys, listen.
If you take the water and you sort of,
like, spin it like this,
- and then hit it... Listen.
- [glass clinks, rings]
See that? It's like a vibrato.
[clinking continues]
[Jane] Bifrost is the key?
[Waititi] Guys, we're in Abbey Road,
and I can imagine the Beatles
just sitting in here, just doing
this kind of stuff, like going...
[clinks glass]
"Ooh, let's put that in.
Just turn that backwards."
Then that would be
the beginning of a song.
All right, here we go.
First time they're all face-to-face
with Gorr the God Butcher.
Okay, guys, probably not... Now's...
No wind chimes probably for this bit.
- [Matewa sighs] Okay.
- [Waititi] Though, let's try it.
Do you think it's going to be...
[Te Kainga] Let's just do
some bad guy ones.
[Waititi] Some bad guy ones?
Hang on, wait.
Let's... Listen.
Just, like, small, small...
[clinking glasses softly]
- [Waititi] No, doesn't work.
- [Te Kainga] Yeah, does not work.
Gorr doesn't like it.
[Waititi] I think go like this. Shh.
[glass clinking]
[Thor grunting]
We really have to stop
meeting like this.
Call the axe.
I'll call the axe
when you call the dentist.
Call the axe.
Tell me where the children are
or I'm gonna kill you.
[Waititi] Okay,
so we actually, um, debated
whether or not
Gorr was too scary for kids.
- Kids, what do you think?
- [Te Kainga] I like him.
- [Waititi] Go... Gorr? This guy?
- [Te Kainga] Mm-hmm.
- [Matewa] He's not scary.
- [Te Kainga] He's not scary.
- [Waititi] You don't find him scary?
- [kids] No.
[Waititi] You're gonna talk,
talk into the mike.
- [Te Kainga] He's not scary.
- [Matewa] He's not scary.
[Waititi] What, you're just cool
with people who look like that?
[Matewa] Yeah.
[Waititi] With sharp teeth
and glowy orange eyes?
- [Matewa] Yep.
- [Waititi] He's...
[Te Kainga] I've watched worse.
[Waititi] I do not want to hear
about Stranger Things.
- [Te Kainga] I'm not talking about that.
- [Matewa] It's not Stranger Things.
[Waititi] Okay.
I said he's nothing like you.
That's right.
I'm not a hypocrite.
I'm truly creating peace.
Peace? You're murdering innocent gods.
Innocent?
Are you a Valkyrie?
[glasses clinking]
How exciting!
[tapping hard surface]
[Te Kainga] No, that doesn't work.
[Waititi] I'm trying to...
How about this?
- Listen to this. Shh. Listen.
- [Te Kainga makes hissing sound]
[Waititi taps wooden object]
When the women you loved
laid dying on the battlefield?
Did you beg them for help...
as your family was massacred?
Good chat.
This one.
You're interesting.
You're different.
Yes.
Aw...
You're dying.
I'm sorry.
We're on the same path.
Just as the sword empowered me,
the hammer empowered you.
But it did nothing to change your fate.
The gods will use you,
but they will not help you.
There is no eternal reward for us.
[Jane grunts]
She'll be gone soon.
And you know who won't help her?
- I'll give you one guess.
- [Thor groans]
[chuckles]
I know your pain.
Love is pain.
I had a daughter once.
I put my faith in a higher power
hoping it would save her
and she...
died.
[sighs]
Now I understand.
My daughter is the lucky one.
She does not have to grow up
in a world of suffering
and pain
run by wicked gods.
Choose love.
Call the axe.
[roots creaking]
Call
the axe.
[muffled groaning]
[Thor grunting]
- [roots creaking]
- [Jane choking]
[grunting]
[Waititi] All right. Here comes a battle
around the tiny moon.
[creatures screeching, growling]
[Waititi] I think this whole thing
looks incredible.
Mmm. I wanna kill this guy.
So do I, but we have to take him alive.
[Waititi] "So do I,
but we have to take him alive, mate."
[creature roars]
[Waititi] Great lighting effects here
created by my friends at Satellite, um,
a New York-based, um,
experimental lighting, um,
tech development company.
And they did
the Valkyrie scene in Ragnarok,
the big flashback where they, uh...
Valkyrie are attacking Hela.
So they're responsible for
that bullet time lighting rig in there.
[Waititi vocalising]
[vocalising continues]
[Te Kainga vocalises
musical soundtrack stinger]
[imitates electrical explosion]
Can you help me with the... Let's sing
a bit of soundtrack. Okay, ready?
Go. Help me. Here we go.
- [Matewa] Of what soundtrack?
- [Waititi] Just here, the...
[vocalises to soundtrack]
[Waititi, Matewa vocalising]
[Waititi]
Goats, goats, goats and the boats
Do big fight between people
With weapons
The weapons have names
In these movies
[Waititi] I have a sore stomach.
- [Matewa] Cool.
- [Waititi] I drank too much coffee.
Uh-oh. She's getting weaker.
What's going on?
You guys notice that?
No. You're drawing.
Uh-oh.
Valkyrie.
- Guys? Valkyrie? No?
- [Matewa] I know. She died.
[Waititi] Wow, you are so just okay
with people just perishing.
[grunts]
[Waititi] Pizzazz. Pizzow. Squizee.
[Waititi vocalising]
[shouting]
[Korg] Hey, guys, we're here.
Come on, let's go.
Stormbreaker, take us home.
[grunts]
- [grunting]
- [shouting]
[Waititi] And he's lost his axe.
What is it with Thor
losing weapons in that Bifrost?
Okay. Well, now the villain
has what he wants.
He's got two weapons.
[Matewa] Valkyrie's weapon.
[Waititi] Pow, pow.
[makes buzzing noise]
[groans]
[Matewa] Didn't Valkyrie die?
[Waititi] Um...
No.
[grunts]
[Matewa] Pretty sure she did.
[Waititi] You didn't see it.
You didn't see her die.
You did not see her die.
You saw her get stabbed.
Look, there are other more aggressive
forms of treatment we can try...
[Waititi] Like what?
I'm sorry, Thor.
[Waititi] He is like,
"I wasn't listening.
I was thinking about having a snack."
- Yeow!
- [clattering]
- Oh, there you are. Okay.
- [Jane] What's goin' on out there?
Oh, some moron made a fridge
without a door. Can you believe it?
[chuckles] Not to worry. Got it open
and got you all sorts of goodies.
How's Val?
Oh, she's in a lot of pain, uh,
but she is stable.
Okay, good.
Now you just gotta get this out of my...
Oh, no, no, no.
That's gotta stay in there.
That's all the magic potions
and elixirs doing their thing, so...
[Waititi] So, this is the effect
of having the hammer this whole time.
He had the hammer with her.
She, underneath it all...
underneath being a superhero,
was getting weaker in her human form.
It'd be great to have you on the
battlefield, fighting Gorr side by side,
but that hammer is killing you.
- "But that hammer is killing you."
- [Matewa] Told you.
What happened to,
"Live like there's no tomorrow"?
Well, that's before I knew
you might not have one.
[Jane] Why not have one more adventure?
[Waititi] "Why not have
one more adventure?"
- [Matewa] Because she's sick.
- [Waititi] That's right.
It's like, you know, what would you do?
You know, would you... like, would you
have one more day as a god?
Would you trade that to be able
to, like, help the world
and to have the power of a god,
or would you not pick up the hammer
and have maybe six months left of life,
but... but being quite sick?
[Matewa] I'd choose that.
[Waititi] You'd choose that
instead of being a god?
- Yeah?
- [Matewa] You're gonna die.
[Waititi] Gonna die anyway.
I think the answer kind of goes
back and forth for most people.
I don't know. I don't think
I can answer that, you know?
I'd love... I would... You know...
For me, probably, I'd take the, um...
Maybe the second option. Just want
more time with, you know, loved ones.
But, you know, some people, uh...
Some people
would just choose the one day.
[whispers] As we're about to see.
Remember that the Gate to Eternity
is at the literal centre
- of the universe.
- Universe. Yes.
If you go past the cluster of comets...
Yes, yes, I know. We've been over this.
I'm not gonna get lost.
[Waititi] Now, I've heard a term called
"fridging" in the last couple of years.
Um...
Is this it? Is this what they mean?
Um, anyway.
Anyway, the point of the matter is...
The fact of the matter is...
The point is, Thor is now alone,
having to go off
because everyone else is injured.
Uh, some of them
happen to be women, but, um...
Also, Korg was... He's a man.
And he got... he got hurt
being around Thor too, okay? So...
It's not just... just the chicks.
Oh, look, guys. Guys, guys, guys.
A very special moment.
Matewa, my daughter, is on film
in a couple of seconds.
Here she comes.
- [Te Kainga] Five.
- [Matewa] Four.
- [Waititi] Three.
- [Matewa] Two.
- [Matewa] Okay. Maybe not now. No, no.
- [Waititi] One.
- And here.
- [Matewa] Five...
- [Waititi] Now.
- ...four...
- [Waititi] Next shot. Watch this.
- ...three.
[Waititi] There she is there,
in the yellow and orange hair thing.
Matewa Kiri. Anything to say
about your appearance on film?
- [Matewa] No.
- [Waititi] What?
- [Waititi] Oh.
Did you have fun that day?
- [Matewa] Maybe.
- [Waititi] Here's what happened.
Matewa did two takes
and then walked off set and said,
"Okay, I'm done. I want my money."
I said, "You've gotta do it all day."
She said, "All day? There's no way.
The costumes aren't real enough.
There's no monsters
and the breaks are too short."
And I said, "Well,
then you're not gonna get paid."
And then she said...
"Ah, it doesn't matter. We're rich."
[Te Kainga] What the hell?
[Waititi] You'll find out soon enough
that money certainly does not
grow on trees.
[Matewa scoffs, chuckles]
[Waititi] Um...
Now...
Also, Christian Bale says he, uh...
he was quite intimidated
by you, Matewa. You...
You really did, uh...
did not care who he was.
[screaming]
I was trying to say,
"But, Matewa, you're gonna
be in a scene with Christian Bale,
the greatest actor
working in our lifetime."
And you were like,
"I don't know what that means."
Go, kids!
[grunts]
Everyone okay? All right, gather round.
Gather round.
Good to see you in person, buddy.
Good to see you.
[Waititi] Uh-oh.
Gorr's not happy about this.
More monsters. More monsters on the way.
- Who's that?
- [Te Kainga] I don't know.
- I made her up.
- [Waititi] That's cool.
Oh, there's Matewa again
in the little blue cape.
Oh, you missed it.
She's wearing a little blue wizard cape.
Well, no time to learn like the present.
[Matewa] I'll be in your next movie,
if you even have a next movie.
[Waititi] What do you mean,
"If I ever have a next movie"?
Of course I will.
- I'm the toast of the town.
- [Matewa] Then I'll be in that.
[Waititi] I'm one of the most popular
filmmakers in the world.
Look, there you are again.
[Matewa] I can see me.
[Waititi] You know what?
They painted me out
'cause I was actually behind you.
I was behind you in a blue suit.
I was holding you there
'cause you didn't want to
do it by yourself.
I was there for moral
and physical support.
- And then they painted me out.
- [Matewa] They painted you out.
[Waititi] So it looks like you're there
by yourself,
- leaning on an invisible nothing.
- [Matewa chuckles]
Today we are Space Vikings!
Present arms!
[squeaks]
[Matewa] My bunny.
Whosoever holds these weapons,
and believes in getting home,
if they be true of heart
is therefore worthy...
[Waititi] Hold the paper
in front of the mike.
...for limited time only,
- the power of Thor!
- [electricity crackling]
[Waititi] Woo-hoo! Child army. Cool.
Um, I love this moment.
This was one of the first moments...
This is the first time we wanted...
That we knew we were
gonna use, uh, Guns N' Roses.
We wanted this moment here with Axl,
with "November Rain,"
and of all these kids empowered with
their little lightning abilities,
and, um, this was kind of cool for them
to fight all these yucky monsters.
There's nothing cooler than when
kids take power over the monsters.
["November Rain" playing]
[Waititi humming "November Rain,"
imitating guitar solo]
Cowabunga, dudes!
[Te Kainga] Hey! There's Octy!
[Waititi] Your monster
just got his head split open.
[Te Kainga] Again.
["November Rain" continues playing]
[Waititi] Fighty, fighty, fighty.
[Waititi] Oh, brutal.
There's Rex.
He just passed the thing to Rex.
[screaming]
[Thor grunts]
[grunts]
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
[Waititi] There's Natalie Portman
from Star Wars I, II and III.
["November Rain" ends]
[rumbling]
[exhales]
[groans]
[grunts]
[Waititi] Oh, no.
[screams]
[Waititi] Thor's on the back foot.
Or just on the back with a foot on him.
[grunting]
[yelps]
[children] Yeah!
No.
- [electricity crackling]
- [horse whinnies]
Jane.
[grunts]
We destroy that sword and he's dead.
The gateway's almost open.
You gotta stop Stormbreaker.
[Waititi] Okay. You stop Stormbreaker,
I'll take the bad guy.
Here we go.
Oh, kids are still fighting.
Stormbreaker, stop this!
[Waititi] Okay,
as soon as that rune is complete
with that Stormbreaker light...
that gate's gonna be opened.
[Waititi] Look how cool
this fighting is.
I'm not saying fighting's cool,
but I'm saying that this fighting,
this fighting looks cool
and that Natalie looks awesome.
Now here's what they call
a bad ass moment.
The name is Mighty Thor.
And secondly...
if you can't say Mighty Thor...
...I'll accept Doctor Jane Foster.
[Matewa] Foster!
[Waititi] Yeah! You know it, girl!
And thirdly...
Eat my hammer!
[Matewa]
Normally, people say, "Eat my dust."
[Waititi chuckles]
Normally, people say, "Eat my dust"?
Oh, man.
What if she'd said, "Eat my dust"?
I think you say "eat my dust"
when you're running away.
Or, like, you just, like, disappear
and you leave a little cloud of dust.
Or you just get a lot of dust
and you put it in a sandwich,
and then they eat it, and you're like,
"Ah, you're eating my dust."
Did you know that dust is made up of,
uh, dead human skin cells?
- [Matewa] Yeah, I know.
- A lot of it.
So "eat my dust" is just saying,
"Eat me."
[Matewa, Te Kainga chuckling]
Eat my dead skin.
Bro.
[Matewa] Want some dead skin, bro?
[Waititi] Hey, bro,
you want some dead skin?
[Te Kainga] Just eat some
of this dead skin. [chuckles]
Slash dust.
[Waititi] Okay, here we go.
Very important moment here.
The Necrosword is about to be destroyed.
They're working together.
He knows it's her last moment
of being a god.
And with her last moment,
she's going to save the day.
Now that's sacrifice.
[Te Kainga] "Now that's sacrifice."
That's you, Dad.
- "Now that's sacrifice."
- [Waititi] Oh, I'll sacrifice, bro.
[Te Kainga trills]
- [Te Kainga trills]
- [Waititi vocalising soundtrack score]
Yeah, yeah, yeah
- [Matewa] So sad.
- [Waititi] Totally.
[Matewa] Totally.
- [thunder rumbling]
- [electricity crackling]
[Matewa] Did Thor and Jane
do kissing rehearsals
before they actually kissed?
- [Waititi] Thor and Jane?
- [Matewa] Yeah.
- Or did they just...
- [Waititi] Kissing rehearsals?
- [Matewa] Yeah, they kiss.
- [Te Kainga] Is that even a thing?
[Waititi] They don't need...
You don't need to do kissing rehearsals.
[Matewa] Like kissing practise.
- [Waititi] Yeah. No, you don't.
- [Te Kainga] No.
[Waititi playing synthesiser]
[Matewa] Dad, now is not the time.
[Waititi] Yes, now is the time
to make it sound like Dune.
[synthesiser continues playing]
Gorr! Stop!
- [Waititi chuckles]
- [Te Kainga] Oh, my God.
[Matewa] Okay. I want to listen now.
It's not death or revenge that you seek.
[Waititi imitates synthesiser vibrato]
What do I seek?
- [synthesiser stops]
- [Waititi] It was just me adding my own...
You seek love.
Love?
- [Waititi] Careful. Don't do that.
- [Matewa imitates] Don't do that.
[Waititi] Okay.
What do we want?
Love. When do we want it?
- Mmm, not sure.
- [Matewa chuckles]
[Waititi] Important moment coming up.
So this is when Gorr sees really
that Thor's right, because it...
The whole thing
that's been driving him is what?
We think it's revenge, but it's actually
because he misses his love.
- [Te Kainga] Daughter.
- [Waititi] The daughter.
- That's right.
- [Matewa] Indi.
[Waititi] Indi. Well, you know,
we say that the name...
[Te Kainga]
Not technically his daughter.
[Waititi] We say that
the name is "Love."
[Te Kainga]
And it's not technically his daughter.
[Waititi] We say her name is Love.
Should we get a little photo outside
on that little zebra crossing?
- It was a famous zebra crossing.
- [Te Kainga] But does it really matter?
[Waititi] Uh...
Well, it does to me.
- [Matewa] What's a zebra crossing?
- [Waititi] Be a nice thing.
I'll show you the picture
from the original thing.
[coughs]
[Waititi]
Be super original for us to do that.
[Matewa] Super original.
[Waititi] So original. Oh, my God.
So... Oh, my God, we're really
talking over this super emotional scene,
and that's very disrespectful
to the acting
and to the emotion and to the drama
and to the complete character arcs
that we are witnessing right now.
And we're making noise, and we're making
fun of it by going like, "Oh, my God."
Um, can you just put that envelope down
for a second?
[Te Kainga] I'm just gonna do one thing.
[Waititi] What?
[Te Kainga] Tape this to that.
[exhales]
[Waititi] Okay, now, can we just
watch the end of this
and pay some...
pay our respects to Jane Foster,
and also show some respect
to the fine acting in this film?
- [Matewa] Thor: Love and Thunder
- [Waititi] High five.
[Matewa chuckles]
[Waititi] Um...
And slow and behold, check it out.
He... He... He actually wishes
for the return of... Who is that?
- [Matewa] Indi.
- [Waititi] Look at that thing.
The sparkly galaxy girl.
Because it's a child born of Eternity.
So Indi's back. Sorry. Love is back.
And he's now been rinsed clean
of the evilness from the sword.
He's his old self, but he's dying. Sick.
Such has been his torment,
and such has been
the trials and tribulations of Gorr.
I've missed you so much.
I missed you too.
[Matewa] And she's so happy
that he's dying.
- [Te Kainga] Oh!
- [Waititi] Whatever.
- [Te Kainga] No, she's so sad.
- [Waititi] Yeah.
[Matewa] Look at her! She's smiling.
I've gotten an extra life.
[Waititi] You don't know
what people would go...
what your reaction would be
or what your expression would be
in a situation like that.
[Matewa] Actually would.
[Waititi] Some people smile
out of nervousness.
It's like they can't control themselves.
Look, he's smiling. So is she.
You know why? Because they're happy
that they've managed to have love
for that brief moment again.
Better to have loved and lost...
Better to have love for a little while...
As the old saying goes, "Better to love
than... then...
and then after a little bit, break up,
- or have that person die, then..."
- [paper pops]
- What are you stabbing that paper for?
- [Matewa chuckles]
I'm creating.
[Waititi] Creating?
What are you creating? Holes?
[Matewa] Yeah, actually.
[Waititi] You're doing
that Sam Neill thing from Event Horizon.
Very proud of you.
Now I understand wormholes.
[Te Kainga imitates]
"Now I understand wormholes."
[Waititi] Okay, look. Watch this.
Stop it.
- Look at this. Look at this moment.
- [Matewa laughs]
[sighs]
Protect her.
Protect my love.
[Waititi] Okay. Now it's the end
of the film. Watch this.
[Korg] Let me tell you
the legend of the Space Viking...
AKA the Mighty Thor,
AKA Dr Jane Foster.
[Waititi] You gotta do something
pretty special
to get a big statue like that
made of yourself.
You gotta save people.
You gotta save the day.
All right. Look at the kids.
They came home.
- [all exclaiming, chattering]
- Oh, I missed you.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine. I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
- I'm okay.
[Korg] The kids were safe
to be kids again.
- [Valkyrie] Louder, three!
- [all exclaim]
[Waititi] Look, this is the moment
you guys are gonna really want to see.
This is when your dad...
This is when Korg grows his body back.
And he finds love himself.
[all scream]
[Te Kainga] Korg?
[Waititi] Korg. Watch this.
[Korg]... was becoming quite the warrior.
The future of Asgard was secure.
[Waititi] Check it out.
[Korg] Speaking of futures,
I was forging one of my own...
now that my body's grown back...
with a dude I met called Dwayne.
[all chuckling]
[Matewa] Dwayne?
- [Te Kainga] Dwayne.
- [Waititi] Isn't that beautiful?
[Matewa] Aw, that's so cute.
[Waititi] Korg found Dwayne.
[Korg] A little someone who turned him
from Sad God into Dad God.
Breakfast is served.
Bon appétit. [chuckles]
Hello. There you go.
Hey. Breakfast.
Excuse me. What is that?
They're pan-flaps. From Earth.
[Waititi] Pan-flaps.
Mixture of pancakes and flapjacks.
He got it wrong.
Thor got it wrong.
I'm wearing them.
You're not wearing those.
Yes, I am.
[Waititi] This is like she's going
to school.
This is what happens whenever
I've tried to take you guys to school.
It takes this long.
Thank you very much.
You know what? You wear what you want.
Don't come complaining to me
when your feet get sore, all right?
You'll get no sympathy here from me.
Fine, I'll wear the boots.
Thank you.
Remember what my mother used to tell me.
Listen to the grown-ups...
and if you see anyone scared
or being picked on...
- you look after them, okay?
- Okay.
And most of all, have fun.
[Waititi] Anyway, guys, so listen,
hey, everyone,
uh, thank you so much for listening
and watching and listening.
And I really hope
that you've enjoyed it.
I'll be amazed
if you've made it this far.
What did you do?
I'd most like to thank my, uh,
two friends,
aka, my daughters Te Kainga and Matewa.
Um, thank you so much
for being part of this.
How has it been for you?
- [Matewa] Good.
- [Waititi] Yeah?
Anything else you'd like to say
about this experience or the film?
Protect the nice ones.
I love you, sweetie.
Love you, Uncle Thor.
[Matewa] Mmm...
I have never seen it.
And when you, um... And, like,
when you were actually making it,
I had never seen, um, Korg find Dwayne.
[Waititi] Yes, but now Korg
has found Dwayne.
That was happening when you were...
maybe when you were at school.
- Um, how was your experience?
- [Te Kainga] It was fun.
[Waititi] Great. Okay, cool.
Well, thanks so much for watching.
This has been Thor: Love and Thunder
Um... and...
I hope you've enjoyed it.
Thank you very much for your support.
I'd also just like to say,
just through the credits here...
["Sweet Child O' Mine" playing]
Anyway, take care.
- Thanks, everyone.
- [Matewa] Bye.
Enjoy the credits.
There's some little tags.
Uh, I guess I should talk quickly about
the tag scene. This first tag scene.
I won't wait till the end of the film,
but this tag scene here,
coming up in a couple of secs, um...
Do I need to talk about it?
Maybe I won't. Just watch it.
It's got that guy from...
[Matewa] Taika Waititi.
[Waititi] It's got that guy
from England in it who's...
This guy Brett Goldstein,
who everyone loves.
And, um, it promises something
for the future involving Hercules
and those other characters, um,
Zeus and everything.
And I'm very, very excited
to think that, uh,
that could be a whole new part
of the MCU, uh, coming up.
Okay. Take care, everyone.
Much love. Uh, bye!
["Sweet Child O' Mine"
continues playing]
["Sweet Child O' Mine" fades]
It used to be that being a god,
it meant something.
People would whisper your name...
before sharing
their deepest hopes and dreams.
They begged you for mercy...
without ever knowing if you were
actually listening.
[chuckles]
Now...
you know, they look to the sky...
they don't ask us fo rlightning.
They don't ask us for rain.
They just want to see
one of their so-called superheroes.
When did we become the joke?
[sighs] No.
No more.
They will fear us again...
when Thor Odinson falis from the sky.
Do you understand me, Hercules?
Do you understand me, my son?
Yes, Father.
["Rainbow in the Dark" playing]
["Rainbow in the Dark" fades]
[gasping]
What?
Oh, hey.
Jane Foster.
Heimdall.
I see you're dead now.
Uh, yeah.
Thank you for looking after my son.
You are very welcome here,
to the land of the gods.
Welcome to Valhalla.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/ap3v3
Help other users to choose the best subtitles